Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Staring at two different views on you and no less. Coffee has gone cold, it's like time froze.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: There you go, wishing, floating down, I wish you. It's like I'm always causing problems, causing… I didn't mean to put you through this, I could. We gonna sweep this under the carpet.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: I hope that I can turn back to the time to make it all right On all right for us A promise to build a new world for us too. With you.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Lying down beside you, what's going through your head?
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: The silence in the air felt like my soul froze. Am I just overthinking feelings I can't? This gut feeling I'm trying to get off me ass. I hope we find the missing pieces I'm just
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: We gotta sweep it under the carpet.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: I hope that I can turn back the time to make you all right, all alright for us A promise to build a new world for us to With you in the middle of it.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: the Jordan!
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: That's right.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Notice you shine in the night like the diamond you are.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: I'm good on the side, so I just hope me in the dark. No one's got to know what we do. Shoutin' down the street, show me When you need it, it's your
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: All I hear, and nothing feels better Nothing feels better
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Nothing feels right on me Nothing feels bad. Come on, we don't got it high. Nothing feels like I never say we're just friends, but I swear when nobody's around.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: This is all you've been doing.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Nothing feels bad.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: This is what I gotta make.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Take it back, please sign inside.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Bye!
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Nothing feels bad over there Nothing feels bad Nothing feels bad
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Boom, boo!
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Shawna!
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Don't need nobody.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Just need your vibe.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Shut it up!
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Don't need no talking.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: I can't be, no, no, no.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: I got your body all over my mind.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: I got so hot, I'm off my feet. We up in the clouds with the sun in our eyes.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Show me that don't need no riding Don't need no riding, just need your riding. Show me that I'm so sweet like hinting Don't need no talking, just need your riding.
Audio shared by 100xOmkar: Tellin' me, tellin' me, tellin' me, tellin' me, tellin' me.
100xEngineers: Hey, folks!
100xEngineers: How are you guys doing?
100xEngineers: Can you hear me? Can you see me?
100xEngineers: Let's do a quick check.
100xEngineers: Awesome. Live into the music.
100xEngineers: Hi, Varun. Hi, Shadha. Hi, Sagar. Loud and clear. Thank you so much for the feedback. This was much needed yesterday. But, unfortunately, we didn't get… I debunked the entire solution. By the way, the entire Airtel was down in Bangalore, for some reason.
100xEngineers: And that's why, like, I think we had, like, two internets. But coming back to, like…
100xEngineers: the main part, which I want to discuss… I don't want to, like, start the session with griping about internet, but start the session with…
100xEngineers: A fresh idea of And, I think, in a way, like, it…
100xEngineers: Something which is very personal I want to share with all of you, like, before I just set the agenda for the lecture.
100xEngineers: I actually didn't sleep last night, like, I barely had, like, 3 to 4 hours of sleep, but I was just thinking whole night about the idea of…
100xEngineers: what does that mean in order for us to, like, go from idea to app? Like, I was… I had the entire deck in front of me, I was, like, building all of those, I was prepared for the lecture, I was, like, about to take the lecture, and then suddenly something didn't work, and then I had to, like, reschedule it, and it was, like, the… the thing was stuck in my head, and I was not able to, like, go beyond that.
100xEngineers: And I think the entire night, I was just like.
100xEngineers: beginning things about that what is the next wave of this entire thing would look like, in the sense that
100xEngineers: if I would not have taken the lecture yesterday, if I had, like, one more opportunity to redesign the entire session, based on whatever I knew in last 24 hours, because I read a lot, I read, like, a lot of interesting things which I'll share with all of you, so I…
100xEngineers: threw the entire content into the trash, and I redesigned everything again. And this is… which is what you guys will see right now, and that's why I didn't share any recording yesterday, because I thought.
100xEngineers: I think it's worth, like, sharing the most latest information with all of you, and also something which is,
100xEngineers: Which I personally believe in, right? Because this is something which I can see right now, based on all the people and the alumni who are building things. What are the frameworks they are using right now? I just had a call, by the way, two days ago with one of my students, and he was showing me, like, how he's building the app, and he got first two paid customers.
100xEngineers: And I was like, wow, this is real, and if I can just show the same thing, and
100xEngineers: The question was that The person who spent 6 months in our previous cohort, which is cohort 6,
100xEngineers: and things these guys have learned to get their first paid customer. If I can teach all of those things to Cohort 7 on day one.
100xEngineers: what will change, and what are the things that will change for all of you and for me? And that was a question and starting point, which led me to redesign everything, and I think this is… this is the content which I have. It's gonna be different. It's not gonna be an approach where I'll show you, like, this is a three-step workflow. Okay, let's put the prompt here, or, like, I would say just, like.
100xEngineers: use Lovable or XYZ. I've done that in the past cohorts, in the past workshops, but it's gonna be, like, a slightly different approach. It's about the same thing which I asked.
100xEngineers: To, like, one of my students that.
100xEngineers: What will it take for all of you to get your first paid client?
100xEngineers: And what are the information? I can share it with you on day one, so that you are equipped, and that's how we're gonna start the cohort. It's basically the last lecture, which I do for C6, gonna become the first lecture of
100xEngineers: C7, and that's the context, that's the premise for the whole series as well, and I'll basically start my screen share, and hopefully you'll be able to, like, get something useful out of this.
100xEngineers: I'll directly jump through the problem statement. I think Agentai is clear. We'll talk about the problem first, I'll then ask you some questions, maybe we'll discuss the solution, and then we'll focus on how can we solve this problem. So these are the three things, and the three ways how I've categorized this lecture. The problem, the solution, and the plan, right? What is the plan that we can use to test this entire thing?
100xEngineers: I'll introduce you to my fictitious character, but this is not entirely fictitious. It's the composite of…
100xEngineers: One of the largest segment of analytics engineers cohort audience, and
100xEngineers: Although this problem statement is something which I have picked for this lecture, but it can be applied, and you guys can take inspiration, and you can follow the exact same format to solve your problem statements. I'll keep my chat open, so if you have any questions, you can keep in the chat. Although I'll take, like, some 30-minute break at the end of it, like, after 30 minutes of explaining, then we'll get in the answers.
100xEngineers: But meanwhile, if you have any questions, you can put in the chat.
100xEngineers: So, I'll introduce the case study of Arav here, and Arav Deshpande has 14 browser tabs open, and a Notion page titled, AI Projects to Build. It has 31 entries, he has shipped none of them.
100xEngineers: These are some of the numbers, which the story tells us.
100xEngineers: He has 31 saved project ideas.
100xEngineers: On his Notion. He hasn't shipped anything yet.
100xEngineers: He has…
100xEngineers: 6 months in the loop. He's been, like, watching AI tutorials, watching all the videos, all the news, following 100X Engineers, Warren Maya, and getting all the insights, following the right people on Twitter and Reddit, saving all the posts every week, saving more than 10 posts every week about things, trying all the new tools, whatever comes into the market, he tries. He's the AI power user by core definition.
100xEngineers: And,
100xEngineers: the point of… about Arav here, what I want to share, is that Arav is not a lazy person, and he's also not dumb. He's ambitious, he's smart.
100xEngineers: It's just, he hasn't, like, gotten to a point where he has applied
100xEngineers: everything what he has learned into something which can provide a real-world impact. And that is a gap which I see across not only our award, maybe, like, one student, but across, like, a
100xEngineers: a whole segment of our audience who follow us, who talk to us, and lastly, like, in the last 3 years, the 50,000 people who I spoke to through these workshops, through these programs, all of them share this common trait, which is
100xEngineers: these people are really ambitious, really smart, and what they're lacking is not just one, I would say, tool, or maybe, like, one piece of advice, is
100xEngineers: is something else, and for a long time, I couldn't…
100xEngineers: put a finger on this particular definition that what is the problem and what are these guys lacking. And only after, like, spending 3 years with each and every student, I was able to now come to a conclusion that this could be, like, one other thing. Again, I could be wrong, this is my hypothesis, which I'm trying to build with all of you, but I'll give you, like, a whole framework of how you can do the same thing for your problem statement as well. But this is what I believed and what I learned.
100xEngineers: from my personal journey. And one of the lessons, which is a meta lesson here, is that
100xEngineers: Everything, what you think.
100xEngineers: could be a problem. It starts with an observation, and this observation has to be deeply personal. It cannot come from that, hey, I read this Twitter thread, or I read this, maybe news, maybe I watched a new reel, which got, like, millions of you, telling that, hey, these are the five top ideas to build, projects with, and these are the five, things which YC is asking us to build, and then going after those ideas, and
100xEngineers: building those things. That… In my opinion, in 2026, as a framework, as a starting point, is useless.
100xEngineers: And that's why, like, all other things which I have taught in 2025, 2024 are no longer relevant right now, because
100xEngineers: Software building has been commoditized. Technology, all the tools that you are using, the cloud code, the GPTs, each and every part of it, all of these things
100xEngineers: are now a public, I would say consumer software. Everyone has access to the same thing. If I teach you one tool, let's say Higgs field, or ChatGPT, or using Cloud Code.
100xEngineers: You are not the only one.
100xEngineers: who knows this? There's, like, 50,000 other folks who have learned all of these tools from me.
100xEngineers: And now you are, like, in a competition that who can use the tool in a better way. And what actually makes you stand out from this entire population is that how deeply you know the problem statement, and what are your observations. So.
100xEngineers: coming back to the meta-lesson of this entire thing and how I started, is from a very core and very personal problem statement which I have felt in my career of last 3 years of teaching people, and I've picked a very specific persona, and this is, like, a good template for all of you to think about, that can you
100xEngineers: Stop, thinking about
100xEngineers: problems, or maybe an idea as, I would say a solution which solves a problem for, I would say, like, a mass segment. And try to narrow it down to, like, one single user, one single person. Even if that person could be, let's say, a hypothetical initially, it works, but eventually you might need to find somebody who is a real user.
100xEngineers: In this case, I have met, like, a lot of ROs in my cohorts, who, who have basically faced the same problem, so I built that profile. I could give you, like, the exact specifics as well. But…
100xEngineers: This is, like, one of the ways to start the thinking problem, or thinking about the problem statement. Find something which is deeply personal to you. Find an observation that you have learned in your career, which
100xEngineers: is your domain expertise, which tells you that this is something not any other person can think of, or any other person might not have this same experience, and this is what makes you you. Nawal Ravikant mentioned that this is what he said, like,
100xEngineers: The specific knowledge, which basically makes you you, and if you, like, tap into this, you are not competing with, like, all other people who are also using the tools.
100xEngineers: Coming back to the problem statement once again, so I've introduced you to Arav, and Arav's problem statement right now is that he's smart, he's ambitious, he knows all the tools, he,
100xEngineers: He has, like, all the ideas, but he hasn't shipped anything yet. Because he doesn't know, like, what other things can impact, and how to get started, basically. Because there's, like, too much noise in this.
100xEngineers: space. Being honest, like, I was also in that RS position, like, 3 years ago, before starting 100X, because I was just watching news
100xEngineers: And it was, like, really overwhelming. Even today, it is overwhelming to, like, see every day a new tool getting launched, and, like, learning all the new LLMs, and how they work, and things getting obsolete, so… and I could relate to this character a lot as well, myself.
100xEngineers: Last month, Arav opened Cursor, started an AI sales agent because he was like, this is enough for me, and I want to, like, today ship something, build something, and
100xEngineers: he got 3 prompts deep, he wrote, like, all these prompts, he watched a couple of videos, maybe, like, one of my videos on Lovable, and, like, used the PRD prompt, generated, like, a whole PRD out of it, and, like, put it onto the cursor. And then…
100xEngineers: He had a question he couldn't answer. Who is this for, and what exactly this task does it do?
100xEngineers: to do. He could come up with different project ideas, maybe he can, like, run different rounds with LMs, that will give him some idea, but
100xEngineers: He himself hasn't started thinking about things from the,
100xEngineers: I would say problem-first view, and he's rather focusing on, right now, at this point, building a solution. And that's where, like, he's… could not answer this part that, okay, who am I building it for?
100xEngineers: So right now, he couldn't answer this. He closed the tab, watched another tutorial on MCP instead, because the tutorial finished like a progress, and the blank file did not. And the…
100xEngineers: Cycle continues.
100xEngineers: One of the core things about this persona, and also a problem, is that it is the absence of evidence.
100xEngineers: which is there, rather than the awareness of knowledge, or awareness of AI.
100xEngineers: Earlier, awareness used to be scarce.
100xEngineers: If you ask me, like, 5 years ago.
100xEngineers: people who used to know about, like, certain technologies, stacks, they were, like, highly in demand, like, front-end developers who knew React was high in demand, people who knew specific, I would say, data science and, like, ML algorithms, they were, like, in demand, because they knew the exact… they had the awareness, they knew the exact terms and the keywords, and even if you are a fresher, and you know all the… you have the awareness about the technology.
100xEngineers: There's a high chance that you could get a job, and you could maybe, like, get
100xEngineers: an internship. Right now, that's not true, because
100xEngineers: with LLMs, the information is, like, available to everybody, and
100xEngineers: Araf can define an agent, he can probably, like, define what is an RAG, what is, like, embeddings, and all the other fancy keywords in the AI space. Maybe, like.
100xEngineers: give you, like, different frameworks, which are trending right now. By standard of awareness, he's ahead of most of the team, and that's, to be honest, with a lot of people among you guys who have, like, joined this session. I look at you guys also in a similar way, that you are, quite ahead as compared to, like, masses.
100xEngineers: if I have to, like, compare it with that audience, in terms of AI awareness, you guys know a lot about AI. You guys have, like, been, like, following people and, like, being up-to-date with a lot of things.
100xEngineers: But that's exactly the problem. Knowing about AI has been commoditized in the last 18 months. And what scares right now is ability to
100xEngineers: create one real-world impact, and I know that this is not a very useful insight, because a lot of you might already be aware of this part, but I'm just trying to reinforce this, because sometimes we tend to forget it, that what is that one thing which we are optimizing for each and every day?
100xEngineers: if I were to, like, summarize the whole case study of ARF, and I'll share, like, more details on this, like, over time, we'll build this case study, and I'll try to solve this entire problem in front of you over the series of multiple lectures.
100xEngineers: But I have to just share the two lines, is that he doesn't lack ambition right now, he lacks the navigation method, just like a large share of… a lot of early career professionals around him today.
100xEngineers: Now I have a question to all of you, because I told you the story of this person called Arav, and he's,
100xEngineers: In fact, like, if I give you, like, a more specific detail, I'll share it, like, right after this in a prompt, so you can go through it.
100xEngineers: if this is the problem statement that we are… in our problem statement, I'll say this is the observation which I had.
100xEngineers: What do you think?
100xEngineers: What kind of idea you can share with me today in the chat that would help
100xEngineers: us to solve Aras' problem. First of all, how many of you got the Aras problem? Like, whatever your understanding of the problem, because this was not a problem brief, this was a… this was an observation brief, which I shared, that there is a student who is basically following these things.
100xEngineers: And, this is the current scenario. So this is my observation. Now, I want first one thing, that what do you think the problem statement here is? Do we have any problem, first of all, with ARF?
100xEngineers: Or is it everything, like, fine? I am overthinking right now, thinking about this lecture, just sharing you my, like, 3AM thoughts.
100xEngineers: If you need to point out and just write one-liner, what is the problem statement here? Or what is the problem based on your perspective?
100xEngineers: Direction?
100xEngineers: Navigation support… Abdul said… said, I think the goal is clear, but… lacking…
100xEngineers: the guidance? Yeah. Saying mind statement. Yes.
100xEngineers: Very correctly, what Satish mentioned. Actionable steps. Chris said this.
100xEngineers: Lack of vision on how to use the knowledge.
100xEngineers: RM is in continuous information overload. While being ambitious, he needs to focus on execution over consumption.
100xEngineers: Nailed it.
100xEngineers: Hunch, this is great.
100xEngineers: Yes, I think a lot of you are…
100xEngineers: giving the right direction, and I think that's the whole thesis of this
100xEngineers: lecture, which… which I'm trying to, like, build on top of it, and
100xEngineers: If I scan one more time… I would say, like.
100xEngineers: yes, you got the problem statement right, that there is a lack of direction among Arav, and we need, like.
100xEngineers: if I come back to Hansh Goel's answer, Aram is in a continuous information. He's…
100xEngineers: overloaded with information right now. While being ambitious, he needs to focus on execution over consumption. John said, Aram needs a framework, I completely agree. And now, if you've got clarity about the problem statement.
100xEngineers: Can you think of what is the solution?
100xEngineers: we can give it to Arav, so that Arav can… Hopefully solve this problem.
100xEngineers: What would that solution look like?
100xEngineers: Maybe just in one line, if you can describe that solution.
100xEngineers: First of all, kudos to all the people who have described the problem really well. I was going through the answers, although I could not point out all of you, but I think a lot of you have, like, said the problem
100xEngineers: And, articulated it correctly. Now, let's talk about what is the solution, and because this is the part which I was…
100xEngineers: Going with that.
100xEngineers: How would you solve RF's problem?
100xEngineers: Small steps forward, slow down and focus. Scheduling, shift one at least. Try to focus on one task at a time, rather than messing.
100xEngineers: A structured step-by-step system.
100xEngineers: Slow down and focus on one thing.
100xEngineers: Okay, some people are saying slow down and focus on one thing.
100xEngineers: But how will Arav decide that this is the one thing that I need to focus on?
100xEngineers: Visualization of his time spent, which brings awareness to direction, directionless progress.
100xEngineers: Oh yeah, I have a counter question to Sagar, then. You have mentioned visualization of…
100xEngineers: time spent, which brings awareness, directionless progress. Let's say I give a whole dashboard to Arav right now, which shows exactly where he spends his time.
100xEngineers: After that, what is the first thing Arak needs to do?
100xEngineers: Because he needs to decide, right now, based on all the data. And we can give the data to Arav that, yes, you're spending this amount of time on Instagram, you check your screen recording and things like that, but what will Arav do after looking at the data?
100xEngineers: I love the answers, by the way, like, a lot of… this is actually, like, learning from students right now, and you guys can learn from your peers, like, the kind of observations and answers people are giving is, like.
100xEngineers: Crazy. Mike said, breaking down the problem into actionable steps. Hans said, prioritizing the effectiveness of to-dos and focus on action steps towards a single problem based on the present timelines. He needs a plan.
100xEngineers: Okay, I've… Checked out a lot of answers right now, but…
100xEngineers: One feedback to most people, this is…
100xEngineers: The answers are very vague right now.
100xEngineers: If I'd give these answers to Araf.
100xEngineers: this might help me and you, because we both have the context, and we are… we know exactly, like, where the RF is, but…
100xEngineers: If I share these answers rightly with Arav, I don't think, like, this will actually solve the problem.
100xEngineers: This will just give… maybe some of the answers will give them direction.
100xEngineers: But I don't know, like, if all of this can become a solution which I can hand it to Arav.
100xEngineers: So what some people are lacking right now is the specificity, which, if I have to, like, articulate in better, like, what is a step-by-step thing which our RM needs to do? Is there anything which we know from our experience? Or you guys have tried it out? Maybe you can share that personal anecdote.
100xEngineers: just try to be slightly more specific, because what kind of answers I'm getting, let's say, right now, community, evaluating the idea, using cloud, noise priority, turn his idea into shippable, small shippable product, all of these are giving more directions than the…
100xEngineers: These are, like, more general advice, actually, not even directions. And this is not really helpful.
100xEngineers: Okay, I got, like, one interesting answer from… Walker. Omahar Walker.
100xEngineers: Give Claude one project idea, ask, break this into 7-day tasks, create the simplest MVP, what can I remove?
100xEngineers: use Claude daily for the coding help.
100xEngineers: Let me put my, whiteboard as well here.
100xEngineers: So this is what… Omhar said?
100xEngineers: Give Claude. I need, like, something like this, actually. This is, like, slightly a better answer, because at least I can give these steps to Arav, and say, hey, this is a solution which somebody from my cohort 7 told me, and if you apply these steps, maybe you will be able to solve the problem.
100xEngineers: Akash has, like, interesting answer, like, I'll not scroll at the, like, the last, I would say, the older messages right now, so if you have, like, pasted something like this, can you just, like, repaste it once again?
100xEngineers: This is what Akash has said. Stop consuming.
100xEngineers: Consume lists, open an old abandoned project, map out the broad strokes that project definitely needs, no details, just the main architecture, finish it one step at a time. Finish and ship the project.
100xEngineers: Rishi said, I used a framework when I had too much on my plate. I started off listing out
100xEngineers: Listing it out first.
100xEngineers: Let me put this one as well. This is what Rishi said. Listing it all out first, create a list of high-impact items on top, prioritize on timelines, earliest delivery first started, first item on the project, with a deadline.
100xEngineers: Tanish said, write his current objectives, use prioritization framework to select the most relevant project, prepare P-hardy, and execute the plan.
100xEngineers: Hunch, set, define the goal, outcome, build a plan to reach the goal, focus on execution.
100xEngineers: Do you see a difference? Like, now people are slightly giving more, better answers, just because, like, we have at least some idea in front of us what good looks like?
100xEngineers: And again, like, I won't be able to go through all the answers… Right now, but
100xEngineers: I would definitely take a look at the chat transcript, so we get this transcript from the Zoom right now, and I'll go through all the answers, and maybe try to, like, see if somebody have interesting answers. Right now, I'll pause on these three only, and I'll give you, like, a quick feedback on these things.
100xEngineers: The first feedback…
100xEngineers: After reading all the answers on the chat, and all the answers which are here on my whiteboard, is that
100xEngineers: They all are… starting with… The action first.
100xEngineers: approach. Now, when I say action first, it's that there's a person, and let's say, in this case, Arav, I shared the problem statement of Arav. I asked you what… do you see a problem? You told me the problem statement. And then I…
100xEngineers: asked you, like, can you solve the problem statement? You said, yes, we can solve the problem statement, you share the solution with me.
100xEngineers: All of this is action first.
100xEngineers: But…
100xEngineers: Low evidence solution.
100xEngineers: I'll tell you why no evidence, because
100xEngineers: None of you asked me whether
100xEngineers: there is a way to validate the problem statement or not. None of you asked me, how can we talk to Ara first, before even, like.
100xEngineers: Maybe, like, some people, again, you can't, like, point me right now, because I scrolled and skimmed through some messages, and if you have mentioned that, we should talk to Ara first. Understand whether what we think the problem statement is.
100xEngineers: Whether it is the actual problem statement or not.
100xEngineers: is it something which ARF have tried? Because, let's say, if you have given this to Arav, what if Araf have already tried this out?
100xEngineers: He has already built, like, multiple projects. He is exactly for the same three steps.
100xEngineers: We don't have any information about that. What if Arav has also tried this?
100xEngineers: And we don't have any information in that.
100xEngineers: So the first thing in my…
100xEngineers: experience, and I used to do the same thing, and it's not a very, I would say.
100xEngineers: a wrong approach, because this is, like, how most people start with, like, the moment you… you see an observation, or you look at a scenario, your brain tries to catch the problem, and you try to, like, solve it as soon as possible. This is, like, how most of our brain works.
100xEngineers: And this is exactly the pattern interruption which I want to bring through this lecture and through the entire program, what we have designed for you, is that don't fall back to your intuitions that you have
100xEngineers: learned over time, because there are things which are changing, and there are… the way of building things, solving problems, using technology has changed, especially in the last 3 years, a lot. And things which we have learned over our careers might not be relevant. So, first thing is gonna be, like, understanding our
100xEngineers: intuitions and assumptions at what are the things we do, and then interrupting and breaking that pattern. So one of the patterns I want to break right now is the moment whenever you start with an observation.
100xEngineers: Just like the observation which I told you from the RF situation. And somebody will ask you, or maybe you yourself will come up with a problem statement.
100xEngineers: Once you have thought about the problem statement right now, don't jump into the solution.
100xEngineers: This used to be a method which most people take, and this is a great learning point, but don't,
100xEngineers: Do this part.
100xEngineers: The moment you have the… problem.
100xEngineers: there's an urge to jump to a solution, but the first and the foremost step, which I would recommend is to
100xEngineers: Talk to the person.
100xEngineers: Who is facing… the problem.
100xEngineers: And why talking is important is because talking is a proxy, and you just don't want to talk and do gossip with that person, but what you're looking here is the validation. Because even before.
100xEngineers: Building a solution. Let's say all of you have whatever solution you have given to me.
100xEngineers: I would say, let's go and build these solutions, and once it is done, I'll share with it Arav, and then hopefully Arav will be able to, like, get the problem solved. But the problem with that is, first of all, you will waste your time into doing something which might not be validated by the external user.
100xEngineers: Another thing, even if it is, how do you know this is the most…
100xEngineers: high ROI task, or high ROI thing which Araf can do, and which you can do for him.
100xEngineers: Because there is a mismatch in the reality of, like, what you are experiencing and what you are observing, versus what is actually there. And this is also not a technological question, it is more of a philosophical question, because
100xEngineers: You are living somewhere else, and you have your own belief system, and you have your own perspective through which you see problems, but the person who is facing, they might have their own. And you both are, like, looking at the problem statement from your own lenses, and you might not have the
100xEngineers: full context of whether whatever we are building is actually gonna be helpful or not. So the point here.
100xEngineers: again, is don't build solutions. In fact.
100xEngineers: my framework, which is the updated version of IDEA2App that I'm gonna teach you guys for the next 21 days, this is gonna be our first assignment in this cohort. We will not even gonna build any kind of solution. We will not build any app.
100xEngineers: There won't be any technology or no tool we will be using. Like, we'll be using some tools to capture the information, but we'll not build any tool.
100xEngineers: This is… the idea… to app V2.
100xEngineers: And the whole goal of this is we don't want to build software, we don't want to build tools. We want to first validate the problem statement, and then we need a way to run the experiment. Because once you have validation, then you need to run the experiment.
100xEngineers: And once you run the experiment, you get…
100xEngineers: Just like how science works, because one of the closest way to Get the truth here.
100xEngineers: all of us, we are trying to seek truth here. I hope this is what we can agree right now, because
100xEngineers: We heard about this guy's problem statement, and the problem statement was clear, but this is the only information we have. We don't know anything about Ara's life apart from this, or maybe, like, you have not met him. So what is missing here is the truth, and one other thing what we are trying to do through this exercise is to seek
100xEngineers: the absolute truth. And this entire framework is first… is gonna let you, get access to what is the most truthful statement out there, what is the facts out there, and once you have all the facts, you have validated everything, then you run the experiment, and then you see whether
100xEngineers: Whatever things that you have thinking.
100xEngineers: can actually be turned into an experiment, and you also not only just run the experiment, but you use something which I like to call
100xEngineers: scientific discovery.
100xEngineers: process for… MVP building.
100xEngineers: Now, there are multiple frameworks which I can teach you, and I used to teach this a lot. I'll teach you, like, this is a prompt, I'll share the prompt with you, you can put that prompt into Lovable or any other cloud code, and generate some kind of app, why coded app with you.
100xEngineers: The problem is that it's an AI slob.
100xEngineers: say that I have been responsible, or I am responsible for a lot of AI slob that my past students have generated.
100xEngineers: And one thing which I realized last night also, when I was looking at some of the work which people have done, like, people who have created, like, really high-impact solutions and things that have, like, led to, like, success in whatever way they have quantified, what's say somebody who just, like.
100xEngineers: joined this program and, like, had all the, I would say, information, but still produced the iSlop, what was the difference in these
100xEngineers: people, and I would say the difference was, again, the understanding of true reality. Like, on the one side, like, there was a person who had access to the same tools in the same environment, but they just went deeper into the
100xEngineers: truth-seeking part, they understood the problem statement well, and they solved things around that problem statement, like, whether it means that they built a service, business, or they got a job in that. And that's… that's basically one of the way how we have observed, like.
100xEngineers: what success looks like in this cohort, because it's… it's not only about me sharing some tools and some prompts with all of you, or maybe some, I would say, workflows. I can do that right now. I can tell you, like, these are 5 workflows making XYZ amount of money, and just do that. But that won't work, because
100xEngineers: you'll always be disconnected with the reality, right? And one of the best…
100xEngineers: Framework what we have in order for us to, like, Seek truth.
100xEngineers: And build on top of it.
100xEngineers: to solve problems, do research, is scientific discovery. This is the same process which
100xEngineers: every other scientist has used to develop new vaccines, new medicine, maybe, like, new technology, like internet and AI, and what I want to do is, I want to take the same learnings from that process and put it here so that we can learn how we can use the same
100xEngineers: process to build our first MVP, which we want to run for the next 21 days, by the way.
100xEngineers: So, this is the updated framework, rough design on the idea. I'll give you, like, a more clear version of it right now, and
100xEngineers: as I said, like, this… This was what most people were discussing initially.
100xEngineers: If I come back here… Most people start from the tool, because
100xEngineers: it feels productive. You can see the screens, you can show your friends. There is a thing on the laptop that did not exist yesterday. You can write down things which maybe, like.
100xEngineers: can help you, like, build those tools as well, or maybe, like, share this information with RO.
100xEngineers: But what we are trying to do today is, like, starting from the problem statement, understanding and
100xEngineers: Validating that whole,
100xEngineers: thesis is what we had. And this is also, like, requires us to, like, do some kind of discovery process where we take our observation, test our assumptions against the reality, and seek truth until we get a valid idea. And then, once we have a framework, we test this framework with
100xEngineers: the real people out there, we talk to them, because I can share another advice with all of you, which I shared, I think, in one of the offices, that, hey, talk to your users, and use Momtest, and this is the book, read those books, ask those questions. And I don't know how many of you have tried that, but even
100xEngineers: Today, a lot of people do not know how to
100xEngineers: Talk to people to seek truth, to get validation about your problem statement and idea.
100xEngineers: This is also one of the major problems which I have seen a lot, and…
100xEngineers: In order for us to solve that.
100xEngineers: We need to first start with…
100xEngineers: PRD is a hypothesis problem, because even before writing down a problem statement, I think that the goal here is to build the hypothesis, and PRD is, in this case, is not a specs, a specification, which was in my V1 framework, where
100xEngineers: I can… I can show you, like, okay, this is a format and where you can, like, generate a PRD, but it's nothing but just a fancy prompt which you can paste into, like, AI, and it can generate you a thing. Which is, again, like, a way…
100xEngineers: people used to build things, and I used to build that as well, but I don't think, like, right now, it makes any difference in anyone's life if I give you, like, a PRD approach, and you can generate 100 PRDs. It won't… it won't give you, like, any clarity. Unless, until you have written that prior PRD yourself.
100xEngineers: what we want to do right now, and I'm replacing this entire PRD prompt with
100xEngineers: a scientific discovery method for hypothesis and validation testing. So everything what you learn about this user, say, case study, we're gonna write it down.
100xEngineers: And we're gonna use LLM
100xEngineers: as an evaluator, so that it can hold us accountable, that whatever guesses we have, what are the guesses which are weakened, which means, like, these are the weakests, and what are the guesses which is worth testing? It also, like, helps us to, I would say, put some gates that, if you can't describe your
100xEngineers: Problem statement in a way that is actually tangible and you can verify it in the real world.
100xEngineers: Then there is no point actually building any solution for that problem statement.
100xEngineers: If you can't talk to a certain number of people, and you can't test your hypothesis, there is no point building another MVP, or even sharing that as an advice. So, that is the whole framework setup, which I have, and in order for me to, like, share this framework with all of you, this is the part two of the session, which…
100xEngineers: I will take, and… I'll share this resource first with all of you. Now, the…
100xEngineers: precaution here is don't take all the things right now from this, resource. This is a guide.
100xEngineers: which I have prepared.
100xEngineers: it's… it's supposed to be, like, a post-read, but I'm sharing it right now so that you can…
100xEngineers: Follow along with all the processes, and let me put this on my screen first, so you'll be able to see this process.
100xEngineers: The process of… Getting the discovery and getting and building the hypothesis.
100xEngineers: to get to an MVP plan.
100xEngineers: And, the way how it works is…
100xEngineers: I'll share a skill file with all of you. If you don't know what is a skill file, I'll teach you, and I'll show you this in, like, 5 minutes. But think of it as…
100xEngineers: a set of prompts, references, and everything which I have learned in the last 10 years of my journey
100xEngineers: after talking to all 50,000 students, codified into one single document, and giving it to the LLM so that it can ask you right questions, and force you think critically, and force you, like, get clarity on what you are building. This is what the skill file is right now, and how it works
100xEngineers: It has these entry gates.
100xEngineers: First is, do you have a real observed problem? Which starts with the observation itself. Like, what are the things that you believe are the problem statements, or anything which you observed?
100xEngineers: If you have anything like that, you can start with this. You can just mention yes in this chat. It will go into the next phase, which is the discovery phase. This phase will have the five steps in it, which is
100xEngineers: Understanding what is your observation, what is the subject in this observation, what is the evidence that you can audit, what is the causal chain, what is the falsifiable hypothesis. And if you don't know any of these things, don't worry, because this process will help you guide that, and will also teach you each and everything in a step-by-step manner. Once you build all this part, and once you complete the discovery process, you'll not only have a problem statement
100xEngineers: Which you have maybe, like, Observed or thought from yourself, but you will have a clean subject.
100xEngineers: evidence, way to audit, and a falsifiable hypothesis which you can test against a real-world experiment. And this is exactly where we go to the next phase, which is we start doing the stress testing, and this is your, like, running the simulation for experiment. I…
100xEngineers: Talk to a lot of people, whenever they say.
100xEngineers: we want to build an application, we want to, we have this idea, what do you think about my idea? And this is a common question which I get a lot, and I hope, like, some of you might have been thinking about this, that, hey, I'm trying to build XYZ thing, do you think this is a good idea or not? And you might need a validation from different people.
100xEngineers: I'm the worst person to ask, by the way, this question. And I'll tell you why, because I have a clear incentive for all of you. Even if you have the most terrible idea right now, I will just straight away lie in front of you and say that this is a good idea, and you should build it. And I'll tell you, like, honestly, why I would say that.
100xEngineers: is because I have the incentive attached that I want more and more people to complete this program. I want more and more people to complete the exercises, complete the lectures. And this is my personal incentive, because
100xEngineers: If you don't learn from me, if you don't finish all the lectures, if you don't perform the exercises, then this would be a failure for me. So I have my own personal incentive, and I will tell you that, hey, whatever idea you have, whether it's a good idea or a bad idea, you should build it.
100xEngineers: Now, the problem is that Some people…
100xEngineers: will not get the validation, and they'll just, like, end up building things which might not be needing, right? It's good for, like, practice, like, if you are somebody who's just, like, practicing something, and maybe, like, want to run some experiments.
100xEngineers: You don't need to go through this entire framework, by the way. And there's a precursor to this entire framework, is that this is helpful for people who are looking to seek truth and build something which is valuable to the real world and to the people who are out there. If you are somebody who is just one of
100xEngineers: I would say, play around with the technology, and you want to maybe just, like, do things for fun, and maybe you want to solve, let's say, your own problem, which you might not care tomorrow to convert it into a product, or building something out of it as a capstone project, or any kind of project, then you don't need to use this. This is, like, a more higher level and advanced level
100xEngineers: framework for that. But if somebody who is… who has a vague observation, vague idea, and you want to, like, convert it to a full-fledged plan, and how can you use the scientific discovery method
100xEngineers: and build this falsifiable hypothesis, and run the test simulation. This is the framework which is gonna be helpful for you, and we're all gonna run it, because the first capstone, and even, in fact, this is the first assignment for all of you, is that you guys will run your own discovery process for the next 21 days. Coming back to the…
100xEngineers: Phase number two.
100xEngineers: this is where the mom test simulation comes in, right? I was talking about that why I'm the worst person to ask whether your idea is good or bad, because I always say yes, and I have a bias, and I told you my honest bias behind it. So…
100xEngineers: MOM test becomes, like, one of the easy choice.
100xEngineers: The problem is, even after reading mom test books.
100xEngineers: I have seen it multiple times in my past cohorts, that people still don't know how to take user interviews.
100xEngineers: This is a thing which I have…
100xEngineers: observed even in my team as well. So what I do is I sit with them, I see, like, what kind of questions they're asking to the users, and then I'll give feedback personally to them. Hey, you could have asked this question, which might have helped you to get more insights from this person about whether to test your idea, or how to, say, validate the idea or not.
100xEngineers: And then they learn from that, and then over time, they get better. And this is what I used to do with a lot of students, but I realized this is not the most scalable approach for me, because I can't sit in all the user interview calls with all my students, and then give them specific feedback. So what I did is what…
100xEngineers: whatever I have learned from my personal journey of conducting mom test interviews, and also, like, listening from my students, compiled it into this phase.
100xEngineers: And this runs a simulation which makes LLM behave like your target customer. Like, say, for example, in this case, if you're solving problem for RF,
100xEngineers: This phase will turn LLM itself into an RF, and you can give the whole profile to it, and LLM will start behaving like that. And now your job is to ask question to LLM, which
100xEngineers: will now force you to reverse the roles instead of, like, you writing prompts. LLM will be just writing prompts, and you need to, like, gather the insight. And you run this simulation.
100xEngineers: And then at the end of the simulation, LLM will give you a stress test report card, which is how well you did in this interview, what were the questions you asked, what are the things you could have done it better, and what are the things which could have given you more insights.
100xEngineers: And finally, after this, we produce the MVP plan, and this is where the MVP comes in, and again.
100xEngineers: heads up for all of you who are expecting Harris to build an application, we will not build an app as an MVP, and one of the parts of this MVP is… it's gonna be, like, a way to
100xEngineers: Run an experiment without building any app, but following a step-by-step process that can give you the maximum evidence about, like, whether this is worth building or not.
100xEngineers: And once you have that evidence, it will also, like, hopefully some people will be able to monetize it, because this is the exact same playbook, what some of my students in C6 and C5 are doing, and I'll share some of the case studies from there as well. They have applied the exact same practice, and they have gotten their first paid customers using the same framework. And now this has… I converted every single thing into this whole skill file.
100xEngineers: And you can, like, follow the same part. At least you can run the simulation. You still need to do…
100xEngineers: the practice, and you can… you need to go to the real world and ask these questions and conduct these experiments, but this is the same practice which people have validated again and again in our cohorts, when it comes to, like, building a product and getting the validation for it.
100xEngineers: Now, what do you… what can you expect from this? There is, like, one more gate here. Let's say if you don't have any observed problem statement, which could be for a small cohort of this audience.
100xEngineers: if you are falling in that category, first of all, I feel bad for you, because how can you live a life when you have not observed any problem statement at all? But still, I have some empathy, because
100xEngineers: I don't know, like, what the situation is right now.
100xEngineers: you can use something which I built as part of my V2. This is OPT Coach, and the way how OPT Coach works is…
100xEngineers: In the more simplest manner, it helps you to identify a particular task in your job, or maybe in someone else's job as well. So it asks some simple questions. OPT stands for Operating Model, Process, and Task. This is the role or business function that what success looks like.
100xEngineers: And what do you do? Process, these are the repeating workflows and methods you do to deliver your operating model, which is
100xEngineers: your goal, and task is, like, one specific task that can be automated. This is a discovery process, which came from my consulting framework. I used to consult a lot for generative AI services, where companies used to
100xEngineers: have this problem statement that, hey, I want to use AI, but we don't know, like, where to apply this, then I used to ask them these five questions, I converted these five questions again into a prompt. This became, like, one of the most popular frameworks which we have used in analytics, and a lot of people have gotten some clarity about it. So I still prefer to use it, like, in some days, especially, like, when you're not planning to build a whole series of products, but you're just trying to identify
100xEngineers: the workflow automation opportunities, or the task automation opportunities, you can still give it a try. I'll share this prompt and upload this on the LMS as well, but the way how it works is, it'll ask you what is your job role, what goals and metrics you use to measure success, who are the users, and what are their needs, what are the processes you run to achieve this goal.
100xEngineers: And if you have any tools or systems, once you answer these 5 questions, it will give you, like, a whole task automation list that these are the 5 tasks you can automate in your everyday job, so that you get some clarity that these are the five things, or 3 candidate tasks for me, which is worth automating. And, you can run it for your own job, or you can run it for your friend's job, and you can, like, answer these questions. A good way to, like.
100xEngineers: start something if you have no idea, or no real problem statement, but I believe that some people, will have the real observed problem statement, then you can directly start with the observation, subject, evidence, causal chain, and falsifiable hypothesis.
100xEngineers: Discovery… Will help you to…
100xEngineers: add all these things which I mentioned, and the goal of the discovery process is to build a falsifiable hypothesis with five kill conditions, which means that it will know that when will this problem
100xEngineers: Fail, or this, idea which you are thinking will not work out, and
100xEngineers: After that, it will start doing the stress test, which will rank the most riskiest assumptions. It will run a MOM test interview, where the LLM will become an AI for you, or, sorry, become your user, and then it will take the segment with
100xEngineers: three personas, it will extrapolate all the information from your interview, and then run it through the multiple profiles who are adjacent to your, say, chosen persona, so that you only
100xEngineers: need to interview one person, but LM can, like, run the same simulation across, like, multiple user profiles. And this is based on a research paper which
100xEngineers: is, like, how to use LMs for UX research, and a lot of those things are, like, applied here as part of it. So what you are also getting is a compilation of a lot of things that I have conducted as part of the lecture series and, like, independent topics, but now compressed into, like, one single activity or a guide. If you perform all of these things, this actually, like, saves you at least a month worth of lectures and things.
100xEngineers: which you don't need to watch, but the moment you start, like, performing this, you automatically see the value in all of those things, and you can read out all these prompts, how they have been written, how they've been structured. And this is, to be honest, one of the best ways, in my opinion, to
100xEngineers: to learn, which is basically learn by building, rather than, like, watching tutorials and watching lectures. And this entire thing is, like, forcing you to do that.
100xEngineers: At the end of the phase two, which is stress testing and running the mom test interview, you will get a scorecard that what all assumptions you initially built, these were weakened, or what were assumptions that broke, and what were the assumptions which came to be true.
100xEngineers: And this is where you… you actually get… surface the truth here. And finally, you…
100xEngineers: we'll go to the manual MVP phase, and the reason why it's written manual is because it's not gonna be based on the technology or the product which you wipe code on any platform, but it's going to be a step-by-step manual approach, which you need to perform as an experiment with your target audience. Initially, I have designed it for a 21-day pilot, because I want you to perform this for the next 21 days, which is 3 weeks from today onwards. You guys will pick your
100xEngineers: own observation, use the scientific discovery method to get to the clarity and do the stress test, and then get this 21-day pilot program, and you need to perform this. This is your first assignment. Once you perform this part, you get an executable… first you get the executable MBE plan, you perform this plan, you get
100xEngineers: a report.
100xEngineers: Which is now, experienced and built by you guys. And once you have that, then we are ready for our first project building. Until that, we have not earned the right to build anything. Because, as I mentioned, we are not living in the era where
100xEngineers: awareness used to be scarce. We are living in the era where technology is commoditized,
100xEngineers: I have written this entire book about…
100xEngineers: Code is no longer a moat.
100xEngineers: And this has been, like, one of the, I would say, the biggest, learning for me after writing code for the last 10 years.
100xEngineers: And I mention it, like, very deeply because
100xEngineers: why I did start another tech business, another startup, which is, like, where I'm writing code again. And after 10 years, why I'm, like, leaving code completely. Not completely, but in a sense, like, I'm not using it as one of the ways to build a business as a moat. And I'll talk more about this framework, which I have designed. It says a 3D framework, which I call the data distribution and design, and how, like, these three things collectively, together, helps you build a strong foundational mode. But this comes as a part
100xEngineers: two, once you have validated your thesis, once you have your MVP in front of you, and you have ran the experiment, I will help you to make this and convert this into a defensible business idea, or maybe, like, an idea which you can, like, use
100xEngineers: maybe as part of your freelance journey, or maybe as a side hustle, and it can still defend your Frontier AI Labs, and maybe anyone who is trying to compete with you, and you can have that edge over everyone else.
100xEngineers: That is the part two, by the way, I'll discuss more on that, how do you defend your business? If you're somebody who is already there, I'll discuss, like, maybe, like, in the next couple of office hours, and how will we do it.
100xEngineers: Now, before I go into the details of it, what I'll share is right now how to use a skill file. This is the skill which I have shared with all of you. You can go to this drive link, and you can download this as a .skill file, so this is…
100xEngineers: the Discovery to MVP Coach skill file. Now, how to use this file? You go to… let me move back to…
100xEngineers: Claude. So you go to Claude, and I'm using Claude as an example, but you can also use it with ChatGPT.
100xEngineers: You go to Settings, You go to capabilities.
100xEngineers: and you go to the skills section, this is the customized one, and you need to click on this plus icon. Don't worry if you can't follow along right now, I'll also share it in a written guide, so you can follow that guide. But very easy step, go to settings, capabilities, and then skills section.
100xEngineers: In the create skill part, this is after clicking on the plus icon.
100xEngineers: you can click on this upload a skill file, and here.
100xEngineers: the file which you have downloaded, upload that file. So, like, you can find that file, and this is the file which I have. So this is how it should look like.skill file. Once you have uploaded this file, it should look like this on your
100xEngineers: Cloud, desktop.
100xEngineers: This is…
100xEngineers: everything codified, and how I describe skill is also a codified expertise. We have a whole lecture, by the way, about this, like, how can… how can you, like, re-engineer skill for yourself? Like, we have built a skill system even before skills became popular in the anthropic community. So we were initially building, because I've been working on the agentic research for the last 3 years, when ChatGPT 3.5 came in.
100xEngineers: So we have built, like, a couple of systems around that, and and engineered everything from scratch, and this is something which I teach a lot, and I love to, like, learn from… learn things from first principles. So we'll share more about the insights that how
100xEngineers: the skills are, working, and how it works, and what are the things about it, but for now, just…
100xEngineers: use it as a framework, because I'm sharing it for our next assignment. This is the Discovery to MVP Coach. Go to Anthropic, you can click on this plus icon button, and upload the skill file. Now, how to use this skill? Once you have seen… once you have… once you… once you can see here that this is the skill which is
100xEngineers: There, and you can see, like, there's a lot of things which, as a reference, I have mentioned, like, there's a simulation protocol, there's a mom test simulation. If you want to learn more about each and everything which I spoke about, like, and how I came to this, this, I would say, framework, you can, like, read about all these parts.
100xEngineers: But I'll show you first how do you run this skill file, and you can run the entire discovery process, the scientific discovery process, to build your first MVP.
100xEngineers: The moment you add the skill, you can…
100xEngineers: you should be able to, like, check it out from the skills section here. So, as you can see right now, discovery to MVP Coach is there. I can write slash command. So, slash is also… skills, by the way, are merged into slash command, so if you write slash, you should be able to, like, see your discovery to MVP Coach, if it is successfully installed.
100xEngineers: And you can choose whatever model you want. Let's say I choose the Sonnet 4.6, and
100xEngineers: This is the only step which you need to do to invoke this skill.
100xEngineers: So first, download this skill, then add it to your cloud, and then write the slash command to invoke the skill.
100xEngineers: it automatically takes the whole part, although in my case, I have already done it, like, because, there's a progress bar here, like.
100xEngineers: every time I run this skill, it checks from my previous chat that where I left last time, when I was doing the discovery process. But if you don't want to do that, you can just ask it, like, hey, I want to start fresh with a new problem statement. This is the part which is only applicable for me, but I think if someone else will add this part, I think this is what you guys will,
100xEngineers: She has an idea that…
100xEngineers: It is the first question which will ask, do you already have a real-world problem or a pattern you have noticed you want to stress test? If yes or no. If you type yes, then it will start your discovery phase after this point.
100xEngineers: Now, I have done all of this part, and this entire step in itself is a filtration part for a lot of you. As I said, this is the assignment number one.
100xEngineers: Of building the hypothesis.
100xEngineers: And seeking truth for what you need to build, validating your ideas.
100xEngineers: Let me share the assignment doc as well right now.
100xEngineers: 0.8x speed, right now it is 2x… oh, is it?
100xEngineers: Okay.
100xEngineers: Let me know if you are… You can see this assignment.
100xEngineers: This is the assignment number one, which will walk you through the journey of, like, what you need to do. And, once you perform this assignment.
100xEngineers: You'll be able to…
100xEngineers: Get the first part of your problem statement, which is getting the clarity, what you need to build with
100xEngineers: A real observation, with validation, and with also the plan that you can test out and run it as an experiment.
100xEngineers: Coming back to…
100xEngineers: If you run this skill file right now, again, you don't need to do it, you can do it, like, after the lecture, so there's no hurry in that.
100xEngineers: Once you run this command, I'll just walk you through what are the things you can expect. This is going to be a long, intensive.
100xEngineers: process.
100xEngineers: I didn't use the term scientific discovery just to sound fancy right now, or I just… I didn't use all of these things which I showed you on my screen, so that maybe I can… I can show off that, hey, this is what I know.
100xEngineers: I meant each and every part which I said here.
100xEngineers: And when you actually run a scientific discovery process.
100xEngineers: It is hard. It is harder than what you have done previously. If you have not done any kind of scientific discovery process, you have not written a research paper yourself.
100xEngineers: This is gonna be, like, one of the hardest things, especially, like, in terms of writing any kind of document.
100xEngineers: And a lot of you will actually just drop off from this assignment.
100xEngineers: One of the very core things which I want to be very clear with this assignment, as well as this problem statement, is that this is designed in such a way that it will filter out
100xEngineers: already the low agency people. People who do not have that curiosity, people who do not have that agency to build and solve problem statements, they will not be able to complete the exercise. And, I'm not trying to, like, make you feel guilty, especially people who might not be able to do this, but I'm just trying to give you a reality check.
100xEngineers: That this is what it takes in order for you to, like.
100xEngineers: build something which is, like, meaningful out there, which can create a real-world impact. And, it's a good information for both of us. Let's say, if you are somebody who looks at assignment number one.
100xEngineers: you create the skill, and you apply this entire thing, and you start the discovery process. This discovery process, by the way, can take up to 90 minutes, to some people, to 2 to 3 hours as well, and maybe more than that.
100xEngineers: So some people will start this with, like, full enthusiasm. They will write the prompts, like, just what I was writing here.
100xEngineers: You mentioned that, can I start you more questions and start to ask you more questions?
100xEngineers: If I scroll down, you can see, like, questions after questions, questions after questions. Just two hours to write all the answers, all the questions, and if I keep scrolling down, you can see, like, the kind of things, what it has done for me. I'll… I'll share the entire conversation with you, but this is the amount of
100xEngineers: conversation which I had with Claude, and it's not done yet. It's, like, still, like, ongoing. At the end of it, what I got is the whole plan.
100xEngineers: Is it lagging?
100xEngineers: Let me know if you guys are facing the lag right now.
100xEngineers: Okay. Not in the last 10 seconds.
100xEngineers: Cool, what I was saying is that this is the whole piece of…
100xEngineers: exercise that we need to perform, and it can take up to 90 minutes to somewhere around, 2 to 3 hours as well. And I was just showing you that how much,
100xEngineers: information you need to put in here, and how much questions you need to answer. And some people
100xEngineers: will give up. So, the idea of this assignment is to find the most high agency folks, and
100xEngineers: I'll show, I'll show this, Sagar. I'm just coming to that, but I'm just trying to, like, set the expectation with everybody else that, this is the assignment which will help us to filter out people.
100xEngineers: who I can personally then spend my time, and my team can, like, spend time with you guys to, like, take this problem statement to the next level. And, I think a lot of people…
100xEngineers: Were asking me that, hey, can we,
100xEngineers: like, build something together, can we discuss this idea? And my answer to that is yes, definitely, I want to spend more time with all of you guys, and that's why I signed up for this, and you signed up for this, but I don't want to spend time with people who are not serious.
100xEngineers: And that's the only bar I have. Like, if you are somebody who is serious about whatever you're building, and you have clarity, I would love to talk to you, I'd love to, like, spend time and hopefully build that, whatever you're building, convert it into a business, help you find a job, help you, like, build a side hustle out of it. But you need to show some proof out of it, and this is the best way to show that proof as a first assignment. So, this is the exercise which will take you around, as I mentioned, up to
100xEngineers: minimum 90 minutes to… up to 2-3 hours. You need to, like, answer all these questions throughout all these phases.
100xEngineers: At the end of it.
100xEngineers: Sandeep, I'll add the step-by-step instructions, how to add skills to ChatGPT and to Claude, but right now,
100xEngineers: I'll show you the output of this first.
100xEngineers: after, I think, maybe, if I have to…
100xEngineers: show you a picture. If I click CTRL-P, This is 35 pages.
100xEngineers: 35 pages of conversations. This is what I…
100xEngineers: I wrote here to generate my first hypothesis and the MVP plan with this skill.
100xEngineers: So you can, like, assume that how much…
100xEngineers: back and forth, which I have done here. As a result of this, we get two outputs.
100xEngineers: And this is what you guys will get.
100xEngineers: This is the discovery document of our workflow diagnosis program. So, after running through all of this part.
100xEngineers: And I want you to, like.
100xEngineers: read this chat out, so what I'll do is… I'll share this entire chat with all of you, and you can find this…
100xEngineers: link here. So this is the second tab of the document, Discovery to MVP Skill, and I have shared the entire chat of the Claude, so you can go through each and every answer, and you can see,
100xEngineers: what kind of answers I have written, what kind of answers maybe you can think of, like, for each and every question. Obviously, my problem statement was different, my observation was different. In your case, it could be different, so you can, like, improvise based on that, but this is, how you can get it.
100xEngineers: Now, the output…
100xEngineers: of all of this, I have already mentioned the doc, so this is for, I think, Sagar and anyone else who was asking me. So these two documents I have already mentioned, the discovery document and the MVP plan, these are two things as an output, you will get after running this entire process. For the discovery doc.
100xEngineers: It summarizes each and every part of the conversation, and I'll quickly read it out loud.
100xEngineers: You can… Understood. And compare this…
100xEngineers: observation with what you guys have thought initially, when I asked you, like, what was the problem statement and how would you solve it?
100xEngineers: Here, Claude helped me to… Is it still lagging?
100xEngineers: I will upload all of these things, Baraji, don't worry.
100xEngineers: Is it better now?
100xEngineers: There are a few interruptions.
100xEngineers: Okay.
100xEngineers: Okay, loud and clear? Okay, thanks. I think this, this might be a temporary issue, because…
100xEngineers: I checked specifically today with the Airtel office.
100xEngineers: that… what's… what's going on. If not, let me know, I'll… I'll maybe switch to the different provider.
100xEngineers: Again, don't worry, guys, people who are out of the loop, I will do a quick revision after this, but let me finish what I'm explaining right now.
100xEngineers: This is an assignment which I've been sharing with you, and the assignment is about… you need to turn your vague idea into an evidence-backed hypothesis and a 21-day MV plan.
100xEngineers: Just like how I shared the observation of RF, and you guys have started giving me problem ideas, and then the solution, you will do the same thing, but…
100xEngineers: Slightly different approach, as what we are discussing so far is the scientific discovery method, and for that, I have given you a skill. And once you run the skill, you will get two things as an output, the discovery document and the MBE plan.
100xEngineers: The discovery document will summarize the entire discovery process with you, like, what was your observation, what was your subject? If you remember, this is what we discussed as a part of the discovery process. It has…
100xEngineers: Return that ambitious early career professionals.
100xEngineers: In urban India.
100xEngineers: who are motivated, but when asked to convert awareness into a specific project, they fail at selection, scoping, first proof, they see AI opportunity at the category level, but cannot translate it into a specific grounded workflow worth building. They skip the step of defining the user repeated task.
100xEngineers: Current process, bottleneck input, outputs, and success metrics. So every project starts big, becomes overwhelming, collapses back into consumption. And the breakdown happens before building at the moment of selection or scoping. So this was, like, the observation which we had, and then the subject
100xEngineers: I'll look at the detail of the subject.
100xEngineers: it is defining the demographic, who is our subject here in this experiment which we are running, or the observation we had. We have described, like, the age range, the city location, and also the background, like, what kind of fields it can come from.
100xEngineers: the behavior?
100xEngineers: What is a common behavior pattern among your subjects, which is your target customers?
100xEngineers: they consume AI content daily, they watch AI videos, they save these things, they learn about it, they are more AI-aware and power users, but their shipping behavior is very low, or maybe close to zero. So high consumption, high ideation, but low completion.
100xEngineers: There is a salary band to it, although it's something which is, specific for the problem statement, because I was showing you, like, how to design the pricing strategy, that that is also a part which is built into it.
100xEngineers: And,
100xEngineers: because of that, we need to understand what is the, I would say the purchasing power of your target audience, and this is a good way to also, like, index your product with the pricing. Like, if I'm targeting people who are already earning X amount of money, so I can, like, understand that if I solve a problem for them, how much value it can unlock for these people, and then how much I can charge for that.
100xEngineers: it's not a very detailed pricing calculator, but it's something which will just give you a good head start. I have, like, a whole method of, like.
100xEngineers: understanding the LLM pricing, and then putting a token of that, we'll learn about it once we learn how to, like, use LLMs and LLM-based application. But this is, like, good right now for… as an MVP part.
100xEngineers: Financial, psychological state, the structural state, the stage, all of these things. This becomes the subject
100xEngineers: of our experiment, then there's an evidence audit. How you make the evidence? Student arrives.
100xEngineers: who are failing consistently at selection and scoping, the adjacent one, the passive, the inference one. And you also need to pick what is the one most load-bearing inside here, and the evidence which, if that
100xEngineers: if this fails, then everything else fails for us. Then there is a causal chain, which is, like, what happens, and this… it's all things basically a part of the discovery process, even if you don't understand the terms which I'm saying right now. Once you, like, go through this process, it'll ask you, like, questions one by one, and, like, ask you to describe these things, and from that discussion, it builds up the whole plan.
100xEngineers: This is, at the end, what you get as a hypothesis here. So, what…
100xEngineers: Now, compare this hypothesis with the answers that you guys have written in the chat when I showed you the observation of RF.
100xEngineers: we believe
100xEngineers: That ambitious early career professionals in urban India who are AI-aware but have no ship proof are stuck because they lack a method to convert broad AI possibility into one specific scoped workflow worth solving. If you provide a structured workflow diagnosis system followed by a guided build sprint.
100xEngineers: then at least 60% of active students will identify one real user, map one repeated workflow, build a working AI-assisted version, and present a credible demo or a case study within 90 days. There's a falsification condition, is that if fewer than 40% of active students produce a credible demo with
100xEngineers: 90 days.
100xEngineers: If the number is lower than 40%, then it means, like, whatever our problem statement was and whatever our hypothesis is, is, like, false. And we can, like, go back to something which is… which can, like, again, help us to find better evidence.
100xEngineers: Students complete diagnostic but still do not build, reading… revealing execution as a primary bottleneck. Students do not report proof artifacts as a meaningful career win. And students primarily seeking jobs, income, or placement rather than proof, revealing a different buyer motivation.
100xEngineers: Then there are some claims that this hypothesis is not claiming to be a program producers, like, what this hypothesis is not, so mentioning about those things, and then at the end, the stress test scorecard, like, how will you stress test all of this? And each and every signal, after conducting your mom test, it will give you a whole brief that
100xEngineers: This is…
100xEngineers: What you did, and what kind of questions you asked, and what kind of signals you got after conducting that interview simulation, and what are the assumptions which got weakened, and what are the assumptions which, maybe in some cases, got completely, like, false.
100xEngineers: And then also, like, top 3 risks going into the MVP, like, once you understand these risks, you design the system, you design the processes behind that or around it. So, making sure that you… you, like, understand these risks before, like, going… stepping out in your, say, market.
100xEngineers: this is one part of the document, and then there's an MV plan, which is a 21-day plan. For my case, like, it mentioned, like, each and everything, including the pricing, how many people I should target, what is a screening filter, and it all is…
100xEngineers: the part which I'm trying to again emphasize here is that it's not something which I asked AI to generate for me. It is a discovery process which happened because I was involved in a dialogue. Just to remind you guys once again that this was a product of
100xEngineers: This conversation, which we have done.
100xEngineers: it… if I, like, scroll right now, you can see, like, I have written, like, a lot of my inputs, which are very personal, by the way. It's… this entire exercise I'm doing is not to run a lecture or do a demo with all of you, it's also to solve a problem which I genuinely faced and I observed in my cohorts a lot.
100xEngineers: So, this problem is, like, very same. If you go through this, there are a lot of Arabs on this call right now, and maybe you guys can self-identify and relate to this
100xEngineers: character, which I initially, like, painted on the lecture, but this is a real problem statement with a lot of students, and one of the ways to solve this problem is to make people build things, and make them, like, have that proof
100xEngineers: Which gives them… by giving them some… some sort of structure.
100xEngineers: In a way, what I'm trying to do is, like, I'm trying to solve the same problem by giving you this skill. So it's a meta-lesson within this lesson, that I shared you a problem statement which resonates with the common persona of my target audience, and I shared you
100xEngineers: the solution as a structured framework, which is not only explaining you how this entire framework works, but you guys can apply the same framework for yourself to get out of that
100xEngineers: lack of confusion, and start building more things, and stop just being somebody who saves AI posts, or who watches tutorial, but starts being somebody who actually builds it. So this is a whole meta-lesson about it, and this was a…
100xEngineers: part of it. Now, one thing which I want to share before I…
100xEngineers: take a Q&A break. Here it is.
100xEngineers: There's… There's a whole set of things which is out there on the internet, which basically forced me to
100xEngineers: think about each and everything from scratch, and there would be some open questions as well about the new technologies, like, why we are not using that, and why we are, like.
100xEngineers: Using something which is, like, an old-school approach of doing it. So…
100xEngineers: based on whatever you have heard me saying, and I'll do a quick recap of this, everything, but I'll take some questions right now, and
100xEngineers: And yeah, like, I want to hear from you guys that if you have any questions about this process, how to perform this assignment, or maybe, like.
100xEngineers: In general, about everything what we discuss. After this Q&A, I'll do a quick recap, and then I'll share some insights, some trends which I've observed, which led me to believe that this could be, like, one of the best ways in 2026 to build products.
100xEngineers: Arif calling Ara of, yes.
100xEngineers: Another problem is…
100xEngineers: Most queues are just proxy validations, even from inaccurate sources. I'll talk about it. It's a very important part. Thanks for pointing it out, Sagar. Yes.
100xEngineers: Most SKUs are just proxy validations, even from inaccurate sources, because there are confirmation bias is at play.
100xEngineers: Can this still be used as a stress test for our problem statement? Yes, it can be… this is, as I mentioned, it's a scientific discovery method applied to product building. And, not exactly, like, building any kind of tech product, but an experiment which you can execute.
100xEngineers: without even building any kind of software. So, even if you are not building an app, even if you are maybe just testing your own hypothesis, and you want
100xEngineers: to run an experiment, you can use this skill. If you have an observation and you want to, like.
100xEngineers: check whether this observation is true or not. You can run this… you can use this skill. So, yes, you can try it out. To be honest, even I have not, used all of these scenarios here, so I think this is the first time I'm sharing this as a framework and a feedback. This is also the first time I am…
100xEngineers: sharing this entire skill with anyone. So maybe you guys can give me more feedback that what all areas where it worked well for you guys, what all areas where it didn't work well, and maybe together we can… we can also, like, build on top of it. But,
100xEngineers: Yeah, like, I can personally tell you that
100xEngineers: right now, like, I've been generating a lot of, my own MV plans, and in fact, this is exactly how we started 100x Engineers, like, 3 years ago.
100xEngineers: By not launching another business, or not another, like, tool, or any kind of, like, fancy, say, technology, but by just, like, running a…
100xEngineers: an experiment which is based on our observation, and we build a hypothesis for that, and this was like a blueprint, which I've now codified into a skill, so a lot of you can apply the same part here.
100xEngineers: Does this idea need to be big, or could be small efficient for…
100xEngineers: small court. It can be anything serious. You don't need to…
100xEngineers: like, build a billion dollar business. This is just an experiment, and the goal of this entire experiment is to actually learn
100xEngineers: how to… First, like, convert your observations
100xEngineers: Into something which is, like, a validation, or maybe you would say falsifiable hypothesis, so that
100xEngineers: you yourself learn what is the process of seeking truth in the age of AI, because when every other creator is telling you that, hey, this is gonna get automated, your job is not gonna be relevant, and you have, like, so many noises.
100xEngineers: how would you filter out the signal from that? So this entire thing will also, like, help you build that muscle to filter the noise
100xEngineers: After, like, from this entire… Entire part, let me… Goodness her.
100xEngineers: Are we failing this assignment if we are failing to monetize at the end? No, Shiva. There is… there is no, monetary incentive right now attached as the success criteria for this assignment.
100xEngineers: Even if you're not able to, like, say, monetize this, you will still consider you will finish this part, and you'll still be, like, marked. The monetization piece has been there
100xEngineers: And I think once you, like, run your own observation through it, you will realize that, because it's subjective, that not everybody might need monetization, some experiments, definitely, like, worth, especially, like, anything which is… which you want to, like, run it.
100xEngineers: for, like, serious people, because free experiments do attract a lot of non-serious users, and sometimes it just gives you distraction rather than, like, giving you any kind of signal. So those kind of things helps, but it's not the criteria for, yeah.
100xEngineers: To mark you, like, success or fail.
100xEngineers: Which model should we choose to get better results for these skills?
100xEngineers: No, Yovraj, we don't provide subscription for Claude, but you can use it on a free plan, and you can use this skill
100xEngineers: on any open source model as well. Skill is, right now, is an open standard, so you don't need to stick to one single model. You can use any free version of ChatGPT Cloud, or even any kind of open source model.
100xEngineers: if you look at this entire skill file, and just to, like, give you some clarity, Ubraj, and that's why I said, like, I'll talk more about this in a lecture where I teach you guys, like, how skills work, but
100xEngineers: If you look at this entire structure of the skill file, it's nothing but
100xEngineers: a set of files which are written instructions. So this is a Markdown file, which is a long file which is written instructions, and then it takes references from, like, other files which are here.
100xEngineers: So, let's say this is taking a reference from the MOM test immersion, which is another file. So, essentially, this skill is nothing different, but it's just a set of files organized in a manner to give you a specific type of output. This is where I have codified all my expertise here. So…
100xEngineers: Yeah, you don't need to, like, again, buy the most freemium subscription for anything, just the set of files which are here. You can run it on Cloud, you can run it on ChatGPT. I will share a guide on how to, like, install it for other model providers as of now, but yeah, you're not limited to only one.
100xEngineers: You should have list of problem statements to go with the assignment, right? I… as I mentioned, Sridam.
100xEngineers: Let me come back to that, guide.
100xEngineers: So this is the README file.
100xEngineers: Just read this first.
100xEngineers: This is answering Sriram's questions.
100xEngineers: If you have a real observed problem statement, then you can directly jump to the discovery phase. If you don't have that.
100xEngineers: I would recommend you to start with OPT first, and OPT is my older approach of identifying the workflow automation opportunities. What this will help you is to understand what are the jobs, what's your job role, what do you do, and how can you find something which is… which you can automate using AI today.
100xEngineers: You don't need to automate it perfectly right now, but this could become, like, an observation, because it is tied to your own role, and once you have an observation, again, you need to… you can validate this observation, whether this is actually going to help, like.
100xEngineers: other people as well or not, and you can run this entire observation to this framework. So, no, it is not necessary to always, like, have a list of problem statement with you. If you don't have it, you can start with OPT as well. If you have it, then you can directly answer yes and go to the discovery phase.
100xEngineers: Where to obtain the skill from? I'll upload everything on the LMS right now. I'm sharing this once again.
100xEngineers: Actually, everything is there in this file, by the way.
100xEngineers: So, I'll share this file link once again.
100xEngineers: You can move to this tab, and this is where the skill file is.
100xEngineers: Yes, you can, you can import the skill file in, Gemini as well.
100xEngineers: You can ask Gemini, by the way, itself, you can just upload the file, and you can ask it, like, hey, can you add this skill into your skill?
100xEngineers: Yes, Balaji. I'll show each and everything, like, how to edit all of this. There's a whole lecture planned for this. This lecture is not about, like, building skills, this lecture is about, like.
100xEngineers: Helping you
100xEngineers: Go from a vague observation to an evidence-backed plan, which you can run, test, and hopefully find the idea for your capstone project, potential capstone project.
100xEngineers: And hopefully you can monetize it, and this is basically what is helping a lot of our students in the past. So everything what is… what I personally learned is compiled into that, and this is the minimum
100xEngineers: Number of steps you need to take in order for you to, like, get to the truth and run this as an experiment.
100xEngineers: So right now, the focus is on that. This is the idea to app V2 journey, and
100xEngineers: I'll teach, like, more things about skills in the upcoming lectures.
100xEngineers: In my work, if my client comes out, with the problem statement, will this be helpful to understand problem? Yes, definitely.
100xEngineers: Naked.
100xEngineers: Again, all these questions, you can just try it out. There is no cost attached to using Skill. You can use these skills with free models as well. So whatever observation you have, problem you have, you can use this, use it here.
100xEngineers: Do we have to use this same skill to solve any problem? Does this mean this is skill only for the assignment, or is it for general use? It is for general use, as I said.
100xEngineers: Assignment is due when 21 days, just starting from today, 21 days is a timeline, what we have. Sometimes you might not need 21 days, but this is the timeline which I have set, and once you get
100xEngineers: your MVE plan. The assignment is not to, by the way, just generate the MV plan, it's to
100xEngineers: is to implement the MV plan. And in order for you to implement that MV plan, you need to talk to real users, you need to talk to them. If needed, you can also monetize this. Hopefully, some of you will be able to get your paid pilot in these 21 days.
100xEngineers: And even if you don't get tickbait pilots, you don't need to worry a lot about it. The goal, what we are trying to do is understand
100xEngineers: This entire discovery process, and find more clarity about how can we
100xEngineers: Go from idea to app in, like, much more… cleaner manner.
100xEngineers: Tj, like, if you can just, like, follow this part, I don't think, like, things should be overwhelming for you, because what I'm asking you to do is just answer questions.
100xEngineers: And this is the evidence which I had, like, I just answered question from starting this one to end of, like, all these, like, 50-60 questions which I answered. That is what all I'm expecting from all of you. Even if you don't understand anything from this lecture, I would suggest, like, take the skill, start, like, the skill process, and I'll share, like.
100xEngineers: And the entire process of, like, how do you use the skill in different providers as well. And just, like…
100xEngineers: let LMs ask you questions, you need to answer those things. That's… that's all. If you don't understand anything, this is what the task is. And I don't think, like, anything more than this is needed right now for this. And you will realize that
100xEngineers: Hopefully, like, how much clarity you need, in order for you to solve this problem statement, or any kind of problem statement, and that's the goal for me.
100xEngineers: Yo.
100xEngineers: I'll talk to you, Tanishk, about this personally, because it is not under the topic which we are discussing right now. Maybe, like, we can do an office hour and discuss more of these things.
100xEngineers: So we have to create a real app in 21 days. You don't need to create any kind of app there, you need to run this as an experiment, and to prove that whatever observation you had
100xEngineers: and hypotheses you build, whether it is true or not. That's the experiment. So, no need to build any app, by the way, Dave.
100xEngineers: Because if I show you, like, the plan, what I got.
100xEngineers: And you can check my plan, this is the MB plan. This is, like, day-by-day plan, and in all these days, there is…
100xEngineers: never mentioned about any kind of app building. It's all about, like.
100xEngineers: it's validating the hypothesis that we have built, and it's, like, suggesting you to use, like, existing apps. You can use that, again, there's no restriction on it, but you don't need to necessarily build an app in order for you to, like, get
100xEngineers: to the clarity, like, whether what you're building is, like, true or not. Okay, now, before I, like,
100xEngineers: say, end the session, I have to share something which is…
100xEngineers: important, because it will also not shape this lecture, but it will shape the remaining lectures as well. And this is part of
100xEngineers: where the world is heading, and this is the emerging area of…
100xEngineers: what we are… what we are observing, especially as per May 16th, 2026,
100xEngineers: And let me first paint a picture on the whiteboard for that. Again, I'll use this.
100xEngineers: In the last, I would say, from, like, 1990s, 5 to today, 2026.
100xEngineers: There has been, like, a… Bunch of things which have…
100xEngineers: Changed humanity and, which has impacted what we're doing, starting from the first era, which is 1995 to 2000.
100xEngineers: Do you remember, like, what was a major shift in this era?
100xEngineers: This was the internet, the dot-com bubble, right?
100xEngineers: In 2010, we had the mobile phone, which is when iPhone released, Android became popular.
100xEngineers: In 2000…
100xEngineers: 15 or 14-ish, this is where cloud as a technology came in. I'm just, like, pointing out, on the things of technology evolution.
100xEngineers: And, cloud was interesting because it was a very business-to-business problem statement, what they solved. Like, earlier, before cloud, people used to, like, have everything on all the machines in their offices.
100xEngineers: But with cloud, companies like AWS told us, you can rent all of our machine, and you don't need to, like, buy each and every machine whenever you have, like, more number of customers, and you can scale things better.
100xEngineers: this gave opportunity to a lot of people, and a lot of companies got built. In 2020, I would say.
100xEngineers: 3 or 2, actually 2. This is where LLMs got introduced. LLMs, generative AI, what we are seeing, and then the whole world of,
100xEngineers: Actually, I would say, like, Gen AI, because Gen AI also comprise of both heirlooms.
100xEngineers: Now, what happened in each of these waves is that with internet, people…
100xEngineers: who got these waves early on, they had…
100xEngineers: something called information arbitrage, which means they had a kind of information which other people do not have back then, and they used that information to solve problems for people using the new platform. Here, these were the platforms, if I have to, like.
100xEngineers: check here. So, platform was internet, mobile, cloud, Gen AI, and…
100xEngineers: As each and every milestone, every platform gives possibility.
100xEngineers: For, like, building a whole new set of businesses.
100xEngineers: And this is only applicable for people who understand these platforms well. So, people during 1995 to 2000, who understood how to build
100xEngineers: websites.
100xEngineers: they became really popular, and in fact, they become some of the wealthiest people during that time, because the dot-com era was, like, investors were pulling… putting a lot of money. So, there are a lot of, like, website developers, or web developers, this was, like, a whole freelance community.
100xEngineers: where it got built. There is, like, web agencies, which got started from this era.
100xEngineers: And, printed a lot of money. Same happened here, if you can recall. The mobile app developers
100xEngineers: And mobile app agencies.
100xEngineers: Same happened for cloud.
100xEngineers: In 2022, this is the era where some of my friends, and I don't know how many of you know about this, this is a company called EOS Labs. My ex-co-founder
100xEngineers: Varunmeyer and, Tejas…
100xEngineers: And Harsha, these are the people who started AOS Labs, because I know I was sitting in the same villa, and we were discussing that, hey, there's… this is a new shift. 2022, we had this conversation with the entire team before we exited our last company.
100xEngineers: that, okay, what is the next era, or the next platform which is there, and how we can take the advantage? And Varun, Tejas, Harshal, they…
100xEngineers: Use that platform and built the GenAI…
100xEngineers: services business. Initially, they were doing a lot of,
100xEngineers: freelancing, like, I was also part of that. I was helping them here and there in some of the gigs. And this is… this has basically happened in 2022, where a lot of people have used these Gen AI services as an agency. And I'll tell you, like, what kind of problems they were solving back then, and what kind of problems I was solving for people.
100xEngineers: just… AI workflows, and this was, like, a common part of that, which… which was…
100xEngineers: such an important thing that every single person who were, I think, who can maybe, like, recall from this chat as well, 2022, everybody wanted to just, like.
100xEngineers: add GenAI into their business. And one of the easiest pieces, like, identify a workflow, and then, like, see if LM can solve that workflow, or maybe the diffusion model can solve that workflow. Use that and solve it, and show the, that we are becoming AI native, we are, like, in the…
100xEngineers: in this loop, and we are becoming different. And in order for me to, like, get clarity for what kind of workflows I can build for a company, so usually the my client call used to look like, back in the day, is that, like, let's say this was a client, and one of the clients which I had initially, they were, like, one of the largest
100xEngineers: newspaper company in India, and so this was, let's say, A media client, actually.
100xEngineers: It's a publicly traded company, and one other thing what…
100xEngineers: I used to, like, ask them if they had…
100xEngineers: this problem statement, that where can we use AI in our business? And, so we used to run a diagnostic test for them, that, hey, can you tell me, like, what's the metric? Again.
100xEngineers: What's your… Good job!
100xEngineers: a core mission?
100xEngineers: How do you quantify it? How do you measure it?
100xEngineers: what processes… You follow, and what tasks you perform in those processes.
100xEngineers: This gave birth to a framework, which I compressed it down into, called OPT. So, which is what I shared with all of you as well. This tells me that what is the operating model of a company, what are the processes they follow, what are the tasks in those processes they do, and once we get clarity on these things.
100xEngineers: I use my own intelligence and awareness that, hey, I know that today's customer support can be automated.
100xEngineers: So all the processes which, let's say, are similar to customer support, I can break down those tasks and start, like, applying AI into it, automate those things, and sell the AI workflows. This is what exactly I was doing. I was applying the exact same framework to each and every client. Hersha was doing the same thing, Tejas was doing the same thing at AIS Lab. In fact, today also, they have, like, slightly similar process to this. They do diagnostic calls with different clients.
100xEngineers: and they understand the company's core mission, their metrics, their KPIs, the processes, and then they suggest what other workflows they can do.
100xEngineers: Right now, we are living in 2020.
100xEngineers: Six… This is, like, almost,
100xEngineers: I would say 4 years past that time.
100xEngineers: this entire thing is… is commoditized as well. Like, if you're starting another Gen AI services business today, I think you are late, because there's already companies like EOS Labs and, like, other companies who have, like, built their moat, and
100xEngineers: If you're somebody who is…
100xEngineers: like, starting to think what is the next platform I can take advantage, whether I'm… I want to get a job, like a high-paying job, or maybe I want to start a business, what is that platform shift? Just like internet, mobile, cloudage, and AI, I can bet on. And I think…
100xEngineers: in my opinion, this is where the era of agents comes in, right? And although I'll teach, we have the entire module of agents, for a very long time.
100xEngineers: Agent was just a buzzword, but it was not, like, providing any value.
100xEngineers: It was very specifically in 2026 that models and the capabilities of the agents have actually become better, and they are providing a lot more real-world value. Now, what this opens up is a whole new opportunity and set of opportunities which someone can build, and you can do a lot more with these agents. And that is…
100xEngineers: where I would say, like, most people will end up, like, doing well, because right now there's an information arbitrage.
100xEngineers: the same arbitrage which each and every platform and each and every wave gave you. Like, people who knew about how to build websites, how to build mobile app in 2010s and 2000s, they had this information arbitrage, and they can use that arbitrage to solve problems and sell services, and they could charge, like, better prices than anyone else.
100xEngineers: Same ways, people who understand how to use agents and solve
100xEngineers: Or maybe you can say, like, build… agents to solve… problems.
100xEngineers: are gonna be, like, one of the highest in-demand people right now, and it is actually true, because it's not, like, something which I'm just making up on this whiteboard. Some of you might be already aware of this, but I want to paint a picture of
100xEngineers: what it looks like. Just like I told you 2020… 2022, this is what I was doing.
100xEngineers: to sell AI workflows to businesses.
100xEngineers: If I would be in a same position in 2026 today.
100xEngineers: And I know that this is the platform shift which we are experiencing. What is the approach that I would take today?
100xEngineers: And one of the answers to that is.
100xEngineers: I call this Morwick's Law.
100xEngineers: Actually, I have made my own paradox. This is Hanadex Dual Paradox.
100xEngineers: And I believe that one of the common misconceptions in the entire AI space is that agents gonna take away a lot of jobs.
100xEngineers: if you are doing any kind of, like, boring day-to-day job, which is repeatable, agents can automate that today, and it will become better in next year, maybe, like, 2027. A lot of jobs can be automated. So there's a fear of, like, being irrelevant right now, because agents are becoming better.
100xEngineers: what I believe, and or my hypothesis is… with both.
100xEngineers: This is…
100xEngineers: what I call Hanitex Dual Paradox. It's part of one of my internal slide deck, which I did with my team.
100xEngineers: What we learned in this space is that when AI makes knowledge work radically cheaper.
100xEngineers: We won't need fewer human beings. We will need More for the, things that AI cannot do.
100xEngineers: And this is a combination of… Two principles, which…
100xEngineers: I call Jevin's Paradox. This happens when a technology or technological improvement increases the efficiency of a resource that
100xEngineers: actually lead to an increase in total consumption, rather than decrease, because the cheaper, the more efficient use drive higher in demand. The clear example of this is
100xEngineers: Steam engines, and a lot of people initially thought that, hey, steam engine
100xEngineers: It's basically what employs a lot of people who can put the coals in the steam, and then when the fuel-based engine came into the picture, and this is the same part for, like, horses and cars, when horses
100xEngineers: used to be the medium for the transportation, and then cars, like, Ford invented cars, and they said, like, this is gonna, like, take a lot of jobs, which it actually did, yes. A lot of people who were, like, using horses, they're not relevant anymore, but
100xEngineers: Overall, it increased the demand of how many people can commute right now, because earlier it was capped on how many horses you had, and after that, it became, like, how many cars you had, and the cars production increased. So overall demand for going from point A to point B increased. People started commuting more, and that is what
100xEngineers: the history has told us. It happened with steam engine, it happened with internet, it happened with, media also. Like, I think this was a very recent example which I could recall.
100xEngineers: Do you remember, like, when YouTube
100xEngineers: got popular. This was, like, back in 2015 to 2016 era. I don't know how many of you can, can, like, or maybe, like, were relevant or, were using, sorry, the YouTube back, back then, and this is relevant for those people.
100xEngineers: in that era, I personally felt that the YouTube is gonna just eat up the traditional media in a way that people won't, like, watch news at all, and if anyone can, like, produce news, there will be a saturation point that nobody will actually watch any kind of news, or nobody will consume any kind of things.
100xEngineers: But opposite actually came to true, right? Where, like, now we consume just much more.
100xEngineers: And there's a… the demand for consumption has increased, like, for content consumption as well in the last, like, 5-6 years.
100xEngineers: earlier, I had this perception because I used to watch TV, and I knew that I could only watch TV for, like, say, a couple of hours. I can't watch for 12 hours, but I never knew that I can actually, like, my screen time could go from, like.
100xEngineers: put from 9 hours to, like, some people, like, I have, who are, like, sitting at, like, 10, 11 hours as well. That is the kind of consumption which we never actually
100xEngineers: So, all of this tells you that whenever a resource becomes efficient, the demand for that entire thing also increases. And this is gonna be same thing for the AI. And now, the problem right now here with all the agents and with all the
100xEngineers: the tech which we are building, especially the LLMs, is that LLMs are not Human-like intelligent.
100xEngineers: they have something which I call jagged intelligence, and I'll explain you what it means. But I'll give you an example. What…
100xEngineers: LMs?
100xEngineers: Intelligence looks like today is that there are tasks which are
100xEngineers: really, I would say, easy for computers. Like, for example, coding, mathematics, all of these things, which used to be hard for computers, like, for somebody, like, sorry, human beings, they used to be really hard. Now, with cloud code, like, you can just, like, do, like, some 5,000 lines of code.
100xEngineers: earlier, for that, somebody needs to, like, study four years of degree, and then, like, perform, like, a certain number of exercise, lead code programs, and, like, spend time in the job, like, maybe a couple of years to actually deliver those kind of output and high-quality output. But now computers can do that really well. But there are still tasks which are really hard for computers, and I don't know how many of you have
100xEngineers: seen this example where, first of all, the strawberry example, where for a long time, LMs could not spell how many R's are there in strawberry, and the recent example is where
100xEngineers: you, if you ask LLM, and these are the state of the AI, the Opus, the ChatGPT 5.5 models, that if I… if I have, like, my car wash, which is, like, say, near to my place, should I walk and should I take my car? And most of the LLMs will tell you that you should walk, because this is, like, the path to that is, like, gonna be much more, say, shorter.
100xEngineers: Which is, like, the wrong answer, and you see that this is where the intelligence breaks, because it is not…
100xEngineers: equally intelligent like human beings. It is intelligent for some tasks, it can do those tasks really well, but there's a lot of other tasks which
100xEngineers: it fails, like, these are very basic for human beings. And this is what Morwick's Paradox, like, tells you, and this is where my thesis comes in, which tells that
100xEngineers: We are witnessing one of the greatest reallocation of
100xEngineers: the largest transformation of human labor in the recorded history, where jobs are changing and things are moving fast. But what every single person, and the RF story, was not just a case study for this lecture, it was a case study which I've been, like, working on from the last three years, is that
100xEngineers: What happens to the general population?
100xEngineers: when you have, like, all these things which, again, becoming, like, really smart at some things, and then, can perform, like, a lot of part of your job, and then you no longer be needed, and you don't need to do those kind of things which you're supposed to do, and for which you've been doing, and you're getting salary from last, like, couple of years, how do you prepare for this entire reallocation? And the answer to that is.
100xEngineers: We need to find what are the tasks.
100xEngineers: that cannot be done by this jagged intelligence. What are the tasks that are still difficult for these
100xEngineers: LLMs and AI machines, which humans can do really well.
100xEngineers: And…
100xEngineers: Once we know this, we can supplement the whole demand, because we know, with the Jevons Paradox, that the efficiency has now increased.
100xEngineers: And I've felt this, like, firsthand, because now people expect more output from everybody, right? And even I do this from my team, right? I know that I tell them that, hey, this is the task which Claude can do, like, why are you not using it? Why are you spending, like, a whole day of research manually? And suddenly, the expectation from human beings also has increased, because
100xEngineers: this… This basically tells that, okay, now we have better tools.
100xEngineers: But because…
100xEngineers: this is not the kind of, like, same productivity which we have seen, because it can give you really good output in some areas, but can, like, completely, I would say, give you bad results in another area.
100xEngineers: now we need more human beings, and this is what the 100x Dual Paradox means, is that when AI makes the knowledge work radically cheaper, which means you can build software, you can, like, do analysis right now, you can, like, do, like, mathematics, you can do academics, you can build games, and you can do tons of things right now.
100xEngineers: For which, like, we don't need more human beings.
100xEngineers: But then it creates a massive gap in the capabilities which these AIs cannot do. And because now you have deployed all of these agents in the market, and this is where I'm connecting it back to the problem statement which I shared with you.
100xEngineers: In 2026,
100xEngineers: If you understand this part, which I'm trying to explain, I know it's, like, slightly harder to get it in the first session, I'll keep it, like, as a concurring theme across all my sessions, but if you understand this particular insight, this is the information arbitrage which you can take away from this lecture today. In 2026, if you understand what are the tasks where agents cannot perform well, and where… which are really hard for
100xEngineers: For these agents today.
100xEngineers: which are really easy for human beings. And when mapping those tasks using the Morwex principle.
100xEngineers: And then you can build solutions around it. Then you can find… let's say, okay, if I know that this
100xEngineers: this task, which I'm solving for Arav, needs human in the loop, in the places where it needs to review the plan, maybe make it accountable. And for creating the roadmap, for maybe, like, sending automated emails, agents can do those tasks.
100xEngineers: You design systems, and you start developing these systems which
100xEngineers: leverages the capability of what agents can do best today, and then leverages what they can't and supplement it and connect it with human beings. And you start, like, building these agentic workflows, and this becomes, like, a whole thing which… which basically, right now, is… is getting popular. There are, like, multiple names to this.
100xEngineers: Which means that, every agent
100xEngineers: cannot do all the tasks reliably in any business function. Even, like.
100xEngineers: agents like Devin and ChatGPTs and Claude's agent, they have mentioned that there are a lot of things, and these are jagged intelligence, what Andri Karpathy has mentioned, and I have, like, a couple of talks which I'll share with all of you.
100xEngineers: After that, so what they can't do, first of all, they don't have the memory.
100xEngineers: they don't have a better interface, and I'll talk more about interface in the next lecture. Some agents work with language, some agents work with voice, some agent works with visuals. They don't have
100xEngineers: Database system which is inbuilt.
100xEngineers: An agent is…
100xEngineers: just LLM talking to tools, running in a loop, trying to, achieve a success condition. And I'll,
100xEngineers: And I'll share, like, how to build those things. We have a specific module designed for it. But I'm trying to just give you some picture, like, agents not have, like, a specific backend. Somebody needs to build that backend. Even the agents…
100xEngineers: like, working with, let's say, Shopify today, they might not know exactly what Shopify is. Somebody needs to, like, configure it, somebody needs to link that thing, so…
100xEngineers: This part, and with… And connecting with human and involving human in the right places.
100xEngineers: It's building the entire harness.
100xEngineers: around the agent, so that this agent, which is on paper, looks good because it can solve those tasks, it can perform coding, it can, like, do mathematics, and it can perform all the benchmarks. It…
100xEngineers: Looks good, but in real world, this agent is useless, and it becomes useful only when you add the missing components to it, and you add human in the loop.
100xEngineers: And you design the workflow which can produce the real-world outcome. And you can only do that once you yourself have the clear understanding, and you have validated that whether this business workflow
100xEngineers: Is actually, like, something which we can solve, which can provide value.
100xEngineers: Building this harness around this agent is… Known as Harness Engineering.
100xEngineers: The entire next 2 months is dedicated for us to, like, learn how to make these agents useful, learn how to apply all the things which agents cannot do today.
100xEngineers: How to build systems around it, how to use human in the loop, and each and every lecture, each and every module is dedicated to that, so that you guys will learn how to take the best advantage of this information arbitrage, which, in my opinion.
100xEngineers: It's one of the biggest…
100xEngineers: opportunity today for this era, where we have the agents which are actually, like, giving the real-world value. And if you use all this information.
100xEngineers: you can actually create a lot more value, and this is something which I have a lot of evidence with me, because
100xEngineers: If I just, like, share you some of my Twitter bookmarks, this is what Aaron Levy has said, this is the box founder.
100xEngineers: there's a whole term right now for our deployed engineer. Deploying agents is far more technical of a task than most people realize, and is far more involved than deploying a software. Software generally works same every time, and generally, for the past few decades, has been updated version of XM technology.
100xEngineers: With agents, you are actually deploying the equivalent work output within the enterprise. The customer is effectively using you as a professional service provider for a task, which they expect to get solved nearly end-to-end. This is an important part to note, because this is the expectation change with agents.
100xEngineers: Now, enterprises want you to solve things end-to-end, for which you need to understand the domain really well, which comes back to the same insight which I started the lecture, that you need to know your observations, you need to know
100xEngineers: All this data, and you need to…
100xEngineers: build these hypotheses, which you can validate and test. Because if you can't, then even if I teach you the best framework to build agents, you won't be helpful to any enterprise right now. Because you won't have your own domain expertise, you won't have your own internal system to seek truth, to validate what works for a business.
100xEngineers: what is the end-to-end service look like today, and how can it benefit a certain business, right now? And this is one of the most important missing piece in a lot of engineers today, because engineers learn building things, and including, like, what I have seen a lot in our cohorts.
100xEngineers: But they lack the domain expertise, they lack the part of what I told you today, the validation of their ideas, discovery process, making sure that whatever you're building is actually useful, because building is getting commoditized, and it is actually commoditized right now. Any agent can build whatever you can build as an engineer, maybe if you learn how to build, but…
100xEngineers: Right now, agents cannot
100xEngineers: look at any business, and they can't just, like, give you this insight that, hey, this is, like, things which are… we need to solve, this is where I lack, and this is where the human needs to do.
100xEngineers: Now, this means you need to actually deeply understand the business process as a vendor. How do you understand business process? This is exactly where the skill comes again. You can only understand business processes
100xEngineers: if you run this discovery method, you have the observation, you define the subject, you build the evidence, you have the causal chain, you build the hypothesis, and you stress test your assumptions with real people, with real-world users. So, each and every part of what
100xEngineers: This skill gives you is not only for the lecture, but it's also for the entire
100xEngineers: Hopefully, over the next 1 year, 2 years, whenever we have the relevancy of building agents becoming, say, popular.
100xEngineers: You can use this to understand any kind of process much, much better. You can use it to run experiments to testify these things.
100xEngineers: And this is a very important part for the next, I would say, set of, like, parts, which are getting there as the opportunities, both as an employment and as an entrepreneurship. Companies need help figuring out which models work the best for their workflows. They need extensive eval setups, they need changes. Now, what is eval? If you look at this, this is
100xEngineers: the same part what, again, we are doing in the discovery process. If I, again, show you, like, one part of this
100xEngineers: This was the…
100xEngineers: MVV plan, and this is the stress test report card, the top 3 things which can fail, and the falsification condition. All of this
100xEngineers: It's the same thing what you write for an agent.
100xEngineers: when you want to evaluate the output. So what we are doing here is we are not just building the hypothesis and falsification condition for human beings, but we are learning how to build the eval system both for humans as well as for agents, which is, again, a common skill that a lot of agents cannot do it right now, and it's a skill that we need to learn.
100xEngineers: If you do this, then you will be able to take the maximum advantage, and you can set up these things so that you know what good looks like, and you can use agents in those manners.
100xEngineers: The other part is,
100xEngineers: The tweet where he retweeted this is where Google has mentioned they will recruit the hundreds of engineers to assist clients in embracing its AI and the information. This is not the only part. OpenAI has launched something called OpenAI Deployment Company, and the only job of this company is to
100xEngineers: like, help businesses build and deploy AI tools. This happened in May 11th. This was, like, all of this happened in last one week, so that's why, like, I was telling you, like, I…
100xEngineers: I didn't…
100xEngineers: find the older approach of, like, going from idea to app, like, really helpful, and also, like, just, like, doing things which AI agents can do right now. Rather than we should focus our energy into, like, doing things which these agents cannot, and then understanding, like, how can we contribute
100xEngineers: our human skills, and then, like, best use the technology. Nader has mentioned that
100xEngineers: Now, this is becoming one of the hottest roles, where
100xEngineers: if you possess a combination of soft skills, good communication, having an engineering background, you're up to speed on latest and greatest agent decoding, you're probably able to land one of them. So there's, like, multiple companies who are, like, looking for the same part, and these people are not…
100xEngineers: complete engineers, these are not, like, product people, they are not, like, business. They're intersection of all these three elements. And what they need is, again, if I come back here,
100xEngineers: These are things which these agents cannot do. I will end this lecture on… on this note of what Andre has mentioned about the jagged intelligence.
100xEngineers: Which, I'll share this with all of you right now. And, just watch this video, this is a great video recently. Again.
100xEngineers: Two weeks ago, Andre mentioned it in Sequoia's talk, that… that what he means, and what is the frontier of…
100xEngineers: labs are doing right now.
100xEngineers: So I'll take a pause here. I'll share this as a case study with all of you, both this entire talk, as well as the frameworks, and I hope you
100xEngineers: implement whatever we have discussed so far. I'll share all the resources, I'll put it on the LMS.
100xEngineers: And let's see, like, if we can make the best use of next 21 days. Hopefully, some of you will be able to
100xEngineers: Validate whatever your hypothesis is, and some of you can, like, turn it into a monetizable attempt.
100xEngineers: With that, like, this is the end of the lecture. If you have any questions for me, you can stay back, you can mention those in the chat. If you don't have any questions, this is the end of the session, you can drop off.
100xEngineers: And the flow state has ended, yes. I think I mentioned about flow state in one of the office hours.
100xEngineers: I love getting into flow state. Yeah, this, this has…
100xEngineers: This has been my personal motto. I think, Tanish was asking, right? Like, if you can find more of those things which can put you into a flow state.
100xEngineers: That's… That's the key lesson.
100xEngineers: How do you stay up to date with so much noise? You use AI for that, or follow specific people? Surya, again, this is the same thing which I taught you guys. If you perform the experiment for next 21 days, I think you will be able to
100xEngineers: Get a gist of that.
100xEngineers: internal mental structure.
100xEngineers: I can maybe take a session about this. It's all about, like, building a mental model, right? The scientific discovery process helps you to seek truth in the research field.
100xEngineers: I can apply the same field… same process to build an MVP, and I can also apply the same process to find what is relevant and filter signal from noise in the AI space.
100xEngineers: So a lot of those things are there. I use the same part, like, what is the observation I have? How can I test whether somebody… whatever claims people are saying about the AI tool and technology, what is relevant and not relevant?
100xEngineers: So… In a way, it's a very similar approach, the same discovery method, but applied in a different domain.
100xEngineers: the more you do it, I think the more it will become intuitive. I've been doing it from last, now, I think, a couple of years. I don't know, I think I can't recall it. I started doing it, like, with Avalon first, and that's where I learned it first time. Okay, there is, like, a better way of, like, approaching the product hypothesis.
100xEngineers: Because even before that, we used to do a lot of these experiments based on our intuition.
100xEngineers: And, and yeah, I think,
100xEngineers: Once it becomes a part of your intuition, then…
100xEngineers: You can… you can, like, filter out these noises.
100xEngineers: What is the future of Agentic era? The… from the GenAI workflow to AgentTech era in 4 years?
100xEngineers: Now it's the hottest kill, but what's the future?
100xEngineers: I'll share the future with you guys, but…
100xEngineers: Let me… let me see if I can…
100xEngineers: share one of the interesting insights, which I was just looking at it yesterday.
100xEngineers: Well, yeah, I think I mentioned it… Already… This is…
100xEngineers: This is part of the document which I have already shared.
100xEngineers: In the same document, if you go to External Links.
100xEngineers: This was a representation of what I was explaining, the jagged edge of intelligence, what Andre has mentioned.
100xEngineers: And, for me, like…
100xEngineers: the real question is not about what… what can AI do, or what can agents do. The real question is, what have we learned how to measure? Because
100xEngineers: Verifiability is…
100xEngineers: is actually becoming the next major problem, and I would say the major, major part, and Andre has written a whole blog about it, that…
100xEngineers: And there's a whole, theory about this.
100xEngineers: asymmetry of verification verifiers rule. Very, very beautiful blog written by Jason B about Understanding this whole…
100xEngineers: verification rule. So, verification rule is very simple.
100xEngineers: It says that the ease of training AI to solve a task is proportional to how verifiable the task is.
100xEngineers: All the tasks that are possible to solve and easy to verify will be solved with AI.
100xEngineers: This is the future, and this is also…
100xEngineers: where most of my thesis is based on. Because I've seen it, like, from my first-hand experience, from last 3 years, the progress you can track
100xEngineers: is… happening, and lLMs are getting better at things.
100xEngineers: like maths, coding, games, because these things are easily verifiable. You can check a logic, you can… there's always a right answer or a wrong answer for a mathematical equation. Same for code, you can check whether the code is right or wrong using… by putting it in the interpreter, and games also have this same thing.
100xEngineers: the moment you can verify a task, and the more clean input you can get, the signal you can get for the verification, the more likely it will get automated. Now, but the question is, what about things which are subjective? Like.
100xEngineers: What is the purpose of life? What is the well-being? What does it mean to live a fulfilling life?
100xEngineers: I don't think an AI can give you this. It can maybe, like, simulate a conversation about that, but it won't… it won't have that kind of intelligence that can give you answers like this. It won't be able to… it can repeat the philosophies of the great philosophers, but
100xEngineers: this is the area where the verification has been, like, very low. And,
100xEngineers: So my hypothesis for future for all the agents is that the peak will become, like, much more higher for all these things, and things which
100xEngineers: all tasks that are possible to solve and easy to verify will be solved by AI. Then the humanity
100xEngineers: will be… Around this space.
100xEngineers: Like, the things which are not verifiable. Because there are a lot of things which I believe that we cannot verify, and
100xEngineers: And the humans will still use their skills to… to do that, and I think the ultimate question becomes that, okay, how can you… how can you live a life with… with… with all these things? And maybe sometimes, like.
100xEngineers: Yeah, just, just, just using these things to…
100xEngineers: to not even, like, verify anything, but just to live life, and I think maybe this is why… this is why these things are actually difficult to verify. Again, I don't have, like, a full built theory about it, I'm still exploring and reading a lot about it.
100xEngineers: maybe, like, I think once I have a full built-up material, I'll take a lecture on this. But yeah, this is more like a future of what we are seeing right now.
100xEngineers: Safe job, become well, yes.
100xEngineers: If you're doing anything like astrology or philosophy, then you're safe.
100xEngineers: If you are selling people,
100xEngineers: Any kind of purpose, well-being, you're safe here.
100xEngineers: For coding and mathematics, becoming difficult.
100xEngineers: AI will give that solution, but, Skandan, the problem is, like, we don't have a way right now to verify all these things.
100xEngineers: And we can't achieve HEI, like, with a jagged intelligence.
100xEngineers: So this is also, like, one of the major questions in the AGI research right now, that what…
100xEngineers: Other things, and how can you verify all the things?
100xEngineers: This is a very interesting discussion, which Andrea has also mentioned here, by the way. That's why I shared this video.
100xEngineers: Yeah, become a therapist. Therapists, the jobs of therapists are actually, like, much more in demand right now.
100xEngineers: And, again, I'm not saying it with, I would say.
100xEngineers: I'm not joking about it, but there's… you'll see the 100x dual paradox and the Morwick's Law, which I shared with all of you, again and again, in a lot of field in the next couple of years, that things…
100xEngineers: which require human skills, which AI cannot do, which agents cannot do, because they don't have the verification method built in for those.
100xEngineers: Those are the ones which will increase in demand, and other parts will… well, maybe we'll use, like, agents for that.
100xEngineers: So there will be a concentration of, like, human beings who will use these skills and…
100xEngineers: That's why I believe that this is actually, like, great, because agents and AIs are… AI are making, is making humans more human.
100xEngineers: Earlier, we used to just…
100xEngineers: do things which were not… were not so human, right? I think that's… that's what my learning is.
100xEngineers: Cool, guys, I know I have, like, a couple of more questions. I would love to, like, take all of them. If you still have any questions which I could not answer right now, you can also put it on the Discord. I would love to go through all of them. We'll see, we'll discuss more. I'll see you guys next week. We'll start the entire series for
100xEngineers: learning how to build these systems around agents, learning what are the things we need to do, how to build the backend memory, database systems, all of those parts. And also, like, while we are doing it, I would recommend you guys to complete the 21-day challenge, because you'll get the idea, and hopefully some of you will monetize those ideas. And, that's the…
100xEngineers: wrap, and I'll see you soon. So, wish you all the best for the challenge, and I'll see you next week.
100xEngineers: Bye-bye. Good night.